MUSIC
Today's speaker
is Dr. Gao Shen of medium-Buy Cloud Academy
at the Center for Im👉
of Health andler Gespr Nan Story
o FS is Shu NF Eng
So Dr. Shen
let me introduce
θ i when
study of plant rather than
aching
you
Changed from immobile to moving animals
So it this across two
Both animals and plants are well studied
Then it went abroad
I just listened to talk to you
it comes first to this
Konell University
Konell at Ethika
OK
Behavior-based
Come to Qingxiu
Then after getting a Ph.D., I went to a short Ph.D. university
then postdoc
Then to Kenbridge in the UK
My understanding is the UK
Kenbridge
I just heard his explanation
This is evolutionary
masters are like darwin
right there
this
made some of the discoveries for which he was famous
But I later found out that Darwin didn't seem to have any degrees.
It seems that the family is very rich, so they wander around
The whole world has been passed around
but made a very, very important discovery
the theory of evolution
Today's theory of evolution
I think our Mr. Shen seems to want to break a part of him
let's listen to his speech
Then his teacher Shen's research
Combining many of these cross-cutting technologies
that he
In fact, I saw a theory called game
This Game Theory
remind me of this
I wonder if you have seen this movie called "Beautiful Realm"
This "Beautiful Realm" Ross Crowe
just play a nobel prize winner
That he is because of game theory
nobel prize
That is the application in this aspect of economics
that's just the unfortunate one
I can tell now whether I was at the beginning of this year or last year
Died in a car accident in New York
But this Ross Clough
admired movie star
He also made a movie I just told them about
He also made a warship
not the warships of the american and british navies
Then was chased by French warships
Later ran to an island called Para
called Para
It's called Para, and a lot of it is observed from that side.
from
So this evolution is a very interesting set
Teacher Shen came back to Taiwan around 2010
In the future, we will do very close contact
He won the young assistant award of our central researcher in 2014
This is in Taiwan
If you are a young assistant award, you will get a young assistant
It will probably be smooth sailing in the future
is it like this
so very
But he worked very hard
so early this year
Because I'm the vice president
I want to take a look inside our courtyard
young works
he has an article
Part I Evolutionary Aspects
in Science Magazine
Science
anyway science magazine
It is indeed a top magazine
if you can get on top
is a very remarkable thing
especially if you're at home
able to do research like this
I read the above author
are our local authors
It seems to mean cooperation or not
That's a pretty remarkable achievement
I'm very pleased to see this
Our Central Plains Institute was recently said to be
very unbearable
so today
Seeing so many people come to support me
thanks a lot
We finally have to keep trying
We're working hard to get this new dean thing done
We hope this gives you good news soon
Today I have a chance to have dinner with the President and the Vice President
If you don't believe me, I'll wait for that
I have a picture, and I am alone
So what they tell us is comfort
You're finally doing alright, so don't worry
so we'll keep trying
This Knowledge Court series is a good example
We're here with our neighbors and a lot of young people
Today let's listen to the theory of using the game in this game
How to discuss this very serious "born in sorrow"
Die from a comforting ecological R&D incident
Our secretariat taught me what I must say
Our next feast of knowledge
It's about Nanke archeology
So it's also very interesting stuff
Archeology is not just in the ground
Flowers look at the bones
There are many little questions in it
So welcome to the feast of knowledge next month
come and listen
we warmly welcome
come on teacher
OK, thank you, Vice President.
use my introduction
And thank you all for listening to me tonight
Well, let me state that
This topic is actually
In fact, it was decided a long time ago
It has nothing to do with recent events
But maybe in the end
It may be found that there is still a little relationship
Of course that's what we're talking about
Raw fish optimizes fish eating case
of course i am
Trying to remember this he made a mistake
This is what Mencius said
Then everyone can maybe not see
I can read it to everyone
Actually, I think he will talk later
That is to say, he would actually say this
Is born and died in peace
In fact, in the history of China
he has his usual background
but anyway
that's what he said
from the individual
He gave several examples
It is said that these people who later became very successful
In fact, the process of growing up
all in some very formerly possible
In this humble environment
then he said
This Tianjiang descends to the world
You must first suffer your mind
Tired muscles and painful second stage body skin
And so he talked about this mechanism
that's what he said
Therefore, it is impossible to tempt and endure disputes
Then I talked about some of these
and wait a minute
He became the speaker of this harsh environment
After the impact on the individual
He actually further promotes
It is the invincible foreign patient Guo Hengwang
Then the fuselage also got sick and died in peace
what about here
If you analyze this word carefully
You can see that the first part actually talks about
The twenty-six environment actually has a positive impact on the individual
what about the second part
It is to say that the 26th environment has a positive impact on the group
Of course I'll tell you later
In fact, it was the past two years that I spent
I also spent some time looking at these documents
These are the documents in China
Then I will try to see if there is a more scientific method.
How about explaining the twenty-six environment?
Is it true for individuals or groups
have a positive impact
Of course, obviously, I don't think it fits my intuition very well.
so i'll talk about it later
In fact, we can learn from the example of ecological evolution
Then I will give you some practical examples
go talk about the idea
It is the adaptation of organisms to the twenty-six environment
whether individual
How does it affect the perspective of the group?
I just said that
In fact, after reading these Chinese literature,
Only to find out that in fact, birth is better than death
It turns out that of course I don't understand very well
If you guys have experts wait a minute
can teach again
That is to say I look like there are mainly two parts
pros and cons
A lot of people refer to it as called priority awareness
But the other part is that
really bad environment
That is actually in the study of philosophy
It seems that priority awareness is more important
so feel like saying
No matter what the environment, people must have a sense of priority and danger
Then I'll talk about it later
In fact, I think Mencius made a big breakthrough
In fact, he thinks that
environment itself is important
not only you have this awareness
Then from the perspective of life
wait a minute i will tell you
That is to say, in fact, for individuals and groups
The impact of the environment will actually be very different
because for the group
is always what you're going to think about saying
Performance of selfish individuals and groups
The two may sometimes be together
sometimes conflicting
Then let me simply introduce to you
In fact, this phantom consciousness
The word Youfan is in Chinese
It may be the earliest appearance of this fine word calculation in the Book of Changes.
He actually introduced a book about Zhouyi
Then say why that did
At that time, King Wen made this Sutra
It's actually for that era
is the generation is not very good
So he has state-owned people
So I made this idea
And actually, I think in our culture
I often hear this
That is to say, for example, people are far away from laws and disadvantages.
that you have to think about saying
something bad might happen in the future
you're going to prepare for this
Then, just like Fan Zhongyan said, worry about the world's worries first
So in fact our culture is actually
I have always encouraged everyone to think about it
You have to think about what to do if you say something bad
I'll talk about it later
In fact, I think this is only part of
And this part is often
i'm in our real life
there are many misused
In addition, what I want to talk about today
A big theme is to say
The impact of harsh environment
I just read this
In fact, Mencius thought it was a bad environment
I will be tempted and bear to dispute what I can't
That is, if he thinks
If you encounter a lot of bad situations alone
many setbacks
In fact, you will think about it
what can i improve
Then maybe you can make yourself better like this
Then like this Ouyang Xiu he will talk
How hard it is to help Yingyou get up
That is to say, when everyone faces setbacks
Whether it is a country or an individual
Sometimes it might not be so bad
In the end, I will mention this example later.
It's from Sun Tzu's Art of War
In fact, I think this is a very classic example
Wait a minute, in fact, it also fits well in our idioms and pictorial media.
That is to say, this investment king, He Zhun, is limited to the field, so that future generations
The reason is that I will talk about it later.
Actually it's about the group
In fact, there are many times when a group needs a very harsh environment
Only then will we let go of ourselves and work together to achieve things
OK, let's just tell everyone
Wait a minute, the speech will be divided into three parts
It's basically my past research
Three types of emphasis
The first is the impact of the ecological environment on idioms and pictorial media
Then to the Nepalese Malay Dirty Worm
And then finally the impact on this distribution of this spinal cord animal
Well, in fact, the birth control history mentioned earlier
same everyone can remember
In fact, I will keep mentioning, that is, the ecological environment
Effects on all aspects of animals
The first thing we want to mention is the total
game theory
Then of course game theory is
It's the game
Talking about how your strategy should change with other people's strategy
of course
The game is everywhere in this
then i won't talk very carefully
What are the games in it?
But you could say it's basically the idea of ​​strategy
then we study
The species studied in the first part was the crested plum
The crown feather plum is a unique species of bird in Taiwan
In fact, if you go to the mountains in Taiwan
is that it is very commonly seen
It is basically the most common in mountainous areas in Taiwan
The most commonly seen bird species
What about what we're going to talk about later?
just a lot of it
In this special book on appreciation of cooperation published this year
We have been invited to write one of the
Then the crown feather plum is very special.
is that it has a very special social organization
monogamy
One husband and one wife share one dynasty, that is to say
In fact, they have an obvious pairing relationship.
Then what
This high-ranked pair and this red-ranked pair
Then they will defend a field together
Then they will order together in the same nest
Then what
The orderly thing is that they are the high-ranking companions
Pairing and red-ranked pairing
they actually
often just nest together
Hatching eggs and feeding babies together
What about the whole world?
About 9% of bird species
It is the case of cooperating to have a child together
but only about less than 20
There are about 10,000 species of birds in the world
That's why there are about 900 species that reproduce cooperatively.
but only less than 20 species are used together in one nest
then you can imagine that
In fact, using a nest together has many disadvantages
like
You probably don't like being with strangers very much either.
living together in the same place
That is, social life is full of conflicts.
That's but on the screen basis
it can share a nest
then take care of
So we can study how they work together
how to resolve the conflict
Then this is just a basic introduction to some idiomatic language media
What about idiomatic media?
His main breeding group just mentioned
Consists mainly of individuals who are not relatives
Then we only need most of the biological social groups
are with relatives
Then there is the idiomatic medium
He actually lives in groups for the most part.
He has very few individuals that are
alone and these pairs of individuals
is very unstable
mean actually
Almost all idiomatic discourse-mediated groups
are with others
Especially when working with strangers
So group life is for them
very important part
So we can go to research and say
How does he maintain a stable cooperative relationship?
Let me tell you about these photos
In fact, if you see idiomatic media in the wild
it's almost always in a group
they do everything together
you can see bathing together
rest together eat together
even sleep together
is their feet
Then this is our social circle
It's just him sleeping and huddling together like this
Then there is the place we studied in Taiwan
He Huanshan, I haven't reached He Huanshan yet
National Taiwan University Coal Wind Experimental Farm
The risks over there are quite beautiful.
There is a great advantage that
because it is an experimental farm
So there's actually a good way inside
Can let us walk on those roads to chase these birds
This is our net
it's a tall net
This is the consort painting plum
Then we have to grab it and put on the anklet
so we're sort of like their id
we can know who it is
In addition, the concubine painting plum is that its tide is very high
About eight meters on average
In the past, in fact, I have studied crowns and painted cotton since the beginning of Dashan
Before that, it was the founder who started the business
So we used to go to its grass alley very high
It's like I used to learn how to build a scaffold
then or like a circus
this is a bamboo pole
it's me if you can see it
then we
Take a bamboo pole, and then there are two students below, so they pull me by the rope
Then I climb up this bamboo pole
Then because I want to talk about his just now, for example, his
Most of them are not relatives, so we have to draw blood to test
his kinship
Then all kinds of things like this, but they came to me when they had something to do, because I finally crawled inside like this
Then, but later, after I started to study for a Ph.D., I felt
Of course it looks like fun, but it's not fun to climb these grasses in the wild
So later we got this aerial work vehicle, which was just mentioned in Meifeng
has a good road system
then i can tell you
The master who came to repair this aerial work vehicle
When we drive on those mountain roads
Just tell me you can get a license
If there is a need for a construction site
can go to support
Because I can drive better than any of them
Because none of us are driving mountain roads like this
then but what
because it's often afternoon
So there are a lot of roadside assistance
So at that time actually
If you limit the truck
Actually I will save too
Because this car is more difficult to salvage than a truck
and then what else
Because the blame is gone
is that he is actually very small
Of course the picture looks huge
But in fact he's only 12 grams
So it's about that big
Then what we have to do is
Actually a very important job
That's the tide we're going to find him
The only way to find his tide
That is, you have to look at the top of his mouth
When I started my idle poems
Then here is already an idle chef
Royal chef is actually very easy to see
Eyes can probably see his mouth growling
But according to the requirements of our research
In fact, when he started spinning spider silk
Because he's going to weave the leaves together to make this tide
So in the beginning it was idle spider silk
So when we were doing research
In fact, you have to find a way to see him.
It's like a little bit of spider silk hanging from the mouth
then you follow him
and see where he flies
like here's one of his tides
that's why go so fast
It must be found at the beginning of the main tide.
that is
because we later
It is using this RFID called wireless camera
That is, we will punch this chip in his body.
And then we're going to be in his tide
Install this pinhole camera
There is also an induction coil
was still very young
Then
So in order to install these things
That's because he's a tiny bird
So he's actually very sensitive
So when we do any of these operations
actually at night
So I just talked about driving that raw sauce car
There are many times when we actually want to open at night
then in the mountain road
Then what
Um
When the tide starts to build
That means he hasn't placed an order yet
then tell us later
The very crucial result is
Because there was a big conflict when he placed the order
So we're going to
He installed the equipment before he placed the order
What about this hole camera?
After this chip
we can
Just know who does what in the tide
Then what
It is also important to say
He is actually not affected by the weather
That's because everyone knows
Maybe the rainy season will come later this year
But everyone lives in Nangang
should be used to the rain
Of course I don't live in Nangang
but on the mountain
That is, his breeding season starts from March to April
that lasted until about august
That's actually
you can think
That is April and May is the rainy season
Then what
From July to August there will be another typhoon
So in fact, when studying the viewing screen,
the big challenge is
There are many times when the weather is bad
Of course, as I just said, what if you look at it with net glasses?
That is, if it rains or fogs up
Even if you are working hard, the data you collect is still limited.
But we also have installed this
This pinhole camera and this
RFID is after the chip
We can continuously collect the information we want
And it's almost impossible to go wrong
That's what I just said
Because we want to study the impact of the ecological environment on its cooperation and conflict
Then let's take a look at the environment of this mountainous area in Taiwan.
How about the ecological environment
After that, actually
It has five or six months of breeding agent in a year
Then it can be used up to four or nine times in one dose
The biggest challenge for it is to say
Typhoon, heavy rain and this food supplement
So it reproduced successfully, its forty-four probably only succeeded twice on average
And because he is very small, there are many natural enemies that will attack him.
But because he is small, he has no way to fight his natural enemies
Then we will talk about it later, that is to say, his cooperation has a lot to do with these characteristics of him.
In fact, he will continue to fail
Then he couldn't fight against his natural enemy
Of course, there is no way for him to go directly to the typhoon, don’t come, or don’t rain.
So all he can do is say he's actually going to keep trying again
OK, let's see if we can play it
Well, it's a video, but it's actually kind of brutal.
But take a look, this is a shark thrush
This is what our pinhole camera looks like
This black is our induction coil
Then this is a very long experience, that is to say, it is actually a mackerel thrush.
But he is a bird
Then why did it break? It's because something is pulling us. This is the grass.
It's the grass that was actually eaten.
It's just a bird that gets eaten whole.
Then I just said that because it is called Huamei, it is actually very small.
So its natural enemies, for example, are some relatively large birds.
or snakes or poisons
actually eat them
In fact, we often see
Then you can see the blue bird over there
it can only be next to
is vigilance
Then you feel that you are a bit bad, that is to say
It seems that I can only cry next to me
what it can't do
So after a while they will actually move on soon
Just move on to the next slot
Well, there is of course something special about this video, that is,
actually eat their grass
unfortunately that
see later
It's actually something you can't imagine
It's actually mud
This is of course just an incidental question
That is, the United States actually has research
that wild cat
Millions of birds are eaten a year in the US
So dogs don't
cats are wild animals
very big threat
Because they're actually pretty good
good
I just said that
We are actually in the crown shadow screen
I'll talk later
what we see is that
The impact of the ecological environment on it
Of course it hasn't really been said
Well, I'll introduce it later
That is to say, it is actually like this
The concept of being in the same boat
Let me show you a video first
This crown clashes with the Huamei it occurs
The reason it's black and white is to say
This happens every morning
This can be seen in almost all the grasslands where the crown and plum blossoms are propagated.
These are two females
Just now a female has been sitting in the bottom half
And what about this female?
it's a multiple of eight
They'll be the island defenders who lay eggs
the female inside
after it was born
it will always be there
then don't let others in
And then another female who wants to lay eggs like this
it must be squeezed all the time
and squeezed in like this
The other one was squeezed out by it
then you can see
wait a minute you can see
It actually suits us to know it's finished giving birth
Then you see it is still very reconciled
it still has to squeeze it out
so we'll talk later
One of the main conflicts we want to quantify
It's the bloody conflict
they are actually
spend a lot of time fighting
It's just pushing back and forth over there
so we'll talk later
That is to say, we mainly look at three conflicts
One is the egg fight just mentioned
Then the number of eggs laid
and the time when the hatching begins at night
Of course you can say
Why the number of eggs laid
Is it a conflict with the time when the egg hatching starts at night?
the reason is this
when they fight
Actually decide the first
It's the strategy of who can give birth to eggs
as if a female bird
he wants to fuck
Then he managed to prevent
Another hen lays eggs
so the first day
Only this A can lay eggs
and then the next day
Well, both of them are fucked
Then what
But what about this female bird?
he succeeded
Because he successfully prevented others from laying eggs
So if he is on this day
if he also hatches eggs
These three eggs will be on the first day
Just being hatched together, starting to hatch
the bird's egg means
he hatches eggs
So these three eggs will actually develop first
Then the egg develops later
The result is the so-called different skin
You can see that this is
Chick days and chick weight
The situation of different skins
Is it these precocious individuals?
In fact, it will be heavier
That's because the crown hidden without it
it only takes 12 days
baby birds can leave the grass
so you are early
In fact, you can see that this is the weight
The lightest more than one
It comes out about 1.6 grams
but otherwise
Individuals who come out prematurely
It may have reached 3 or 4 grams
so more than double the weight
So this is for their competition
Actually a very important step
So from here the continuation is to say
you have to win you have to lay eggs
Then you hatch the eggs like this
your child can
win at the starting point
Then what
But the other case is that
If you do not succeed in preventing others from
Eggs are born, everyone is born
good
Then, everyone's eggs were spread together
Then it's more likely to happen like this
Synchronization
Everyone is a child, the weight will be closer
Well, let's talk about it later
The ecological environment has a great influence on their cooperation with Xunxi
Next, let's talk about the impact of the ecological environment on him.
The ecological environment we are talking about here is rainfall.
it's raining
then we can see that this is just an indicator
That is to say, when the rain is heavier, it is actually called Huamei.
It is Vietnam that finds food to feed its children
Then why are you talking about this?
In fact, when we were submitting
One of the biggest problems is
That is, everyone is very skeptical
Why is it a bad environment when it rains
why not a good environment
So one of the proofs is that
If you have, for example,
For example, say you go to the mountains and it rains
In fact, the temperature is quite cold
And that is to say, there is a belt of clouds and mist in this plum wind
So in fact we did not analyze
That is to say, when it rains, it often
Cotton-length fish just keeps falling like this
instead of saying like for example if you go
Go to Africa, go to Kenya
I didn't do another study there
rain is short
For example, it rains every afternoon
just download a lot
but otherwise diligent
So for many ecologists
In fact, for them, the heavy rainfall
is a bad environment
It's actually a weird thing
But this viewing screen
In fact, we have several pieces of evidence showing that
In fact, rain is a relatively harsh environment for it.
we can see that is to say
The result is that the black BAR
This is the rather intense conflict just mentioned.
white just step on it
Then you can see this fierce conflict
that is, if it rains
It only lasts about six minutes or so
Actually quite long
It's what they need
This averages six minutes
then but in good weather
it is actually
Sorry, it was about three minutes just now
when the weather is good
it can last longer
can
So in six or seven minutes, just step on there
So you can see that indeed
when the weather is good
He actually has a high level of social conflict
play for a long time
then when the weather is nice
In fact, because I just said
That is, he actually fought for a long time
Then it's more likely that someone will win
So we have analysis
Then something like this would be generated
just someone will wait
will start hatching earlier
It's you who beat Mr. Egg
you start brooding
hatch your eggs
Then the other one might be more intuitive
That is to say, when the environment is good
black eggs
good environment
Everyone lays more eggs
There are more eggs in one tank
That's a bad environment
Everyone lays fewer eggs
but the fun is here
That is to say, on the contrary, these
born at a bad time
black is bad
children born at the same time
Actually in the end
its weight is relatively heavy
where X is the number of days
Y is the weight of the chick
Then this dotted line is in a better environment
On the contrary, its weight is relatively light
The reason is very simple
this is another
Another same result
just behaving differently
is you can watch this
Even though there are few children born in a bad environment
But in fact, there are actually fewer children who die.
You gave birth to a lot in that good environment
many children died
So the result is instead to say
This is to analyze dead data directly
better environment
Because everyone lives more
In fact, more children die
In a bad environment, fewer children die
what about this
It is actually a very common occurrence in social life.
This is called a public tragedy
you just want to say
Because it is a shared dynasty
So if the weather is nice
Everyone is in good health
So everyone will fight
Then you have the energy to raise more eggs
The result is that you actually have more children than you can have
because you're going to compete with you
If you don't give birth to so many others will give birth to more
In fact, this is where we can use game theory to analyze
It shows that this public tragedy actually happened on Guan Yu
Then the best way to prevent it is to say
Because when the environment is bad, you have to cooperate
Of course everyone is interested
I wrote a popular science article on Science Paper
Well, a very important takeaway from this part is that
It is the totality of the same boat just mentioned.
Then I will explain in detail later why this is in the same boat
Then let me show you a video
It's another creature that's actually a lobster.
Sometimes a plan in cooperation with others
Then why is it related to lobster? Let's take a look
Well, the lobster example is quite interesting, that is,
Wait a moment
This lobster generally lives in relatively shallow seas.
but
It has a very special behavior when there is a typhoon
Or when America called the gale
where are these lobsters
It must be taken to a relatively deep sea to cover the typhoon
So the ecological environment here is the typhoon
or the wind
The cool thing about that is when the lobster is pulling
it will form a group
These individuals don't usually live together.
no interaction
But like this play
they will
It's just that the line is getting longer and longer
Great Wall
also like this
such as this line
Well enough
on the first
also like this
that everyone knows
it's still together
also like this
first comparison
that's because
all
as many as five to ten times
Okay, so the phenomenon we're going to study is this
Of course it wasn't me. It was our co-author.
He's an expert on lobsters
And I think the coolest part of his research is to say
I just said that before the migration of lobsters
he actually gets together
and then keep going in circles
So he's going to study this lobster migration
every time there is a typhoon warning
He quickly went into the sea to observe how this lobster migrates
that's fun
This place is the lobster lead.
It will go around in circles. The video just now also talked about
That is to say, it will actually last for varying lengths of time.
that is
just turn around and then
when one decides to be the leader
Because leadership is the hardest
Then other people will follow it like this
what are we going to study
That is to say, in fact, this is what we use models to study
Just use game theory to study
What about this large school or small school of lobsters?
You can think about it, that is, if a group of lobsters
There's someone who's going to be the leader
they don't know each other
Then what
It means being the leader is the one who runs first
or the most tired
So, our research question is
Is it a large school of lobsters or a small school of lobsters?
It will be quicker for someone to come forward
to be the leader
Then everyone can go
Then think about it, don't you?
Do you think the large group will go first?
please raise your hand
good
That's definitely the small group that will go first.
Please raise your hand
wow good
Okay guys, does anyone want to explain why?
Faster and better coordinated
It's that small groups may be easier to coordinate
Just leave as soon as you need to, right?
ok but i just said something
In fact, he doesn't know these people at all.
It's because their lobsters don't usually form groups
It's when the typhoon comes that we gather together quickly
They don't usually live together
Why are there large groups and small groups?
when he gets together
In fact, when they gather
Sometimes there will be more only together
sometimes less
Of course you can talk about why you took that route
Then someone may study that
Maybe with that they can use the magnetic ones to guide
just where to go
Um
Well, actually, of course we do this using patterns.
That is to say, there are actual data
The result is that you can actually see the time
You can imagine that this 1 is a typhoon coming
Then it’s over if Da Luo doesn’t start, the time to start provisionally
Then this n is the group size
Then this probability is the probability of who will become a leader
Then this can be converted into time
That means actually
In January, of course you will leave immediately
you go when you need to go
Then you can see that the ordered thing is to say
What if there are two
Actually it takes a long time
someone will become a leader
What about early January?
The closer the typhoon comes
someone will be the leader
That is to say, when there are actually more people
He will actually drag on longer
That's the actual data
that looks like only five dots
In fact, at that time because he received it a long time ago
so
In fact, he received more than 30 points
just useless to analyze well
But basically when the group gets bigger
In fact, the time he spent waiting
In fact, the longer you wait
Well, this can actually be said to everyone
wait a minute i have
In fact, when the group is larger, it is
you can see that is to say
No one is willing to come out to lead
Well, if some of you can't get sociology
it was said a long time ago
Then say to the social college
Just like our sociology, people also have this kind of
They call it shared responsibility
The most famous example is a man in New York
Then they were chopped
Then I don't know dozens of people saw it
Then no one rescued him like this
It was later proven that the story seemed untrue.
But in short
when more people
no one wants to come out
take on this public thing
but you look at it from here
Just why would someone come out to bear it?
Taking Long Xia as an example
As you can imagine, it is very intuitive to say
In fact, there can never be no one
because of you
Someone has to go
So the situation is that
In fact, there is a lot of pressure
Just need someone to do this cooperation
So the summary is that
Whether it's just infused or not
Or the lobster example just mentioned
a principle that i think is very important
It is the same boat in the same boat mentioned in Sun Tzu's Art of War
That togetherness is actually behind it
has a deep meaning
Then I'll read it for everyone
He said this is nothing
more people are wrong
When they are in the same boat and they want the wind
It looks as old as left and right
Then it means
If you have read history
That is to say, no country follows the country of Yue
It's an enemy country, right?
This Wuwang Fucha Yuewang Goujian is like this
They are actually enemies
That is to say if they
When a boat is about to cross the river
hit this storm
then everyone will help each other
like the left hand helps the right hand
What kind of consciousness is this?
so he said this
That is to say, Qiyong has the right way of nihilism
This is of course the most important sentence
He said that those who make good use of soldiers
Hand in hand to implement a last resort
mean to say
His one is Nine Emperors
It's how you use the emperor form to lead troops
that means he said
In fact, you have to invest your soldiers in the dead emperor
Then save the stone emperor and win
Conquer the counties to the public, serve the counties to harm, and then win or lose
mean to say
actually
when your army
An example like this is an example of being beaten by water
That is to say, when your army is in a black river
Everyone has no centripetal force
Then everyone is a teacher
when you don't want to fight
A strategy you can use is to say
actually
let everyone be
To a
very dangerous environment
It is you who make good use of this ecological environment
make everyone very dangerous
Then what
just if you
If you for example say you want to flee without a fight
you have nowhere to go
That's the so-called dead emperor
If there is reality, then at this time, there is nothing you can do
We had no choice but to work very hard, that is, to cooperate to kill the enemy
What about this, what about the lobster we just talked about about Yiyi Huamei?
what does it matter? actually i think it means
The cooperation of many creatures is like this particle
That is to say, it is like a plum blossom, but it is actually there, and it cooperates
The reason why it is very cooperative is that, in fact, there is no way for you not to cooperate
Because, for example, the environment is too bad
So you don't have the energy to peel raw eggs and fight
The lobster particles mean that if everyone is not together
That is to say, if no one leaves
That would actually become
just like this, everybody dies
So you're saying you're being forced to cooperate
ok that's the first part
Then, I seem to want to speak a little faster
The second part is that we're going to talk about burial bugs.
Then of course why does the burial bug talk about this?
just wait a minute
Actually, I think this burial bug study
with this we humans
Expansion history has a lot to do with
people actually
This is what an ecologist from EOL province said
He said that in fact, people and ants are the same
The two most successful species on this planet
Humans are the most successful animals
is the most biomass
And the ants are the most in the five-year-old
Well if you look at our own natural history
It's been debated for years, of course.
But for example, from 60,000 to 100,000 years
We expand from this Africa to the whole planet
In fact, in a very short time
We have been very successful in expanding to a large area
from an ecological point of view
The question to think about is to say
In fact, if we are in the environment of Africa
how to adapt
slowly in a short time
Adapt to environments from this arctic to the equator
Of course one of the important roles
That is to say, the so-called social conquest
He thinks it's because
People form social groups
So we have developed a lot of capabilities
but
Of course it's because of people you can't do experiments
it's hard for you to prove that
It's because of cooperation
Then of course there is other circumstantial evidence
For example, these changes in brain volume
but i think that means
You need to understand the fundamental problem of human expansion
In fact, you have to study and say this
The relationship between environment and social behavior evolution
So actually?
Of course, it is from why people wait a while to jump to
On this little bug
Because we can experiment
Then in fact in the current theory
just to explain
Why do organisms form social groups
There are two main categories
Ecological Limit Hypotheses
That's actually talking about a good ecological environment.
my middle school face
density becomes high
then this time
In fact, the competitive pressure in this society is very strong.
So this time
Cooperation is actually to counteract the pressure of competition within this species
It's in the species
then you can imagine
I think you may be very familiar with this concept
it's actually like this
The current situation in Taiwan
Everyone fits this example
That is to say, our population density is very high.
so this
What I want to say here is to say
Here is the bio example
this is the year
This is the density of the group
Then what
This was originally a military purpose
This sex is on the small island of Saixi
It has been this for several years
This is the number of fields
This is the number of groups
It is when the group grows to a certain level
cooperation begins
It is here that the cooperative group is formed
that's because it's
You can see that the number of trips has actually not increased
that just said
Why is it very similar to the example of Taiwan?
That is, as you can imagine, it is the area of ​​the island we fixed.
That's because more and more people
So basically this can be done with grass
Then we may just buy a house
It's getting harder and harder at this price
The price is getting higher and higher
So more and more like this bird
We call it offspring delayed dialing
In Chinese, it is called Ken Laozu
That is to say, children can't
Go outside on your own, for example, to build a house or start a family
So these creatures are actually when the density is very high
He really doesn't have enough ability to go
go build a field yourself
So he stayed home and helped
Then this is in the bird
There is a lot of evidence to show that
In fact, many birds are
The relationship between species competitive pressure
So in a good environment
Because of the high level of competition
That's good for the environment, but the competition in the social environment is high
That's why this cooperative group was formed.
But recently there was another
One type of study found that
In fact, the changing environment
On the contrary, many social groups emerged
The reason is because of the changing environment
For example, in Africa, the rainfall is very stable and varies greatly.
That actually needs everyone's help
for children in times of drought
The example of people is actually very famous, that is,
這個It takes a village to raise a child
i.e. need a tribe
Let's help together to take care of and raise a child
Well, that's actually another category.
There are mainly two arguments
There are actually some suitable examples for each of them.
So it is actually a good environment
also promote social groups
An unfavorable environment actually promotes the formation of social groups
So, in fact, this research is relatively more
It is how the chaotic environment affects the evolution of this society
but what about us
Wait a minute for this example
That is to say, very few people actually ask
If the ecological environment promotes the evolution of society
How does that affect the species or group
That's what I just said
In fact, from a human point of view
In fact, it means that after we form a social basis
With this we can expand so fast
does it matter
That's my theory
But to put it simply, you don't need to look at that picture
that means
If you form a social cycle
For example, like Taiwan
is to combat the pressure of species
Its premise is that the density of the ethnic group is already very high.
Therefore, at this time, a social bottom line is formed.
won't help the group
That is, it can be denser
or expand to a wider range
That's another category
If we form a social cycle
is to resist the harsh environment
ecological environment words
In fact, at this time, a social cycle is formed.
should be able to help you
is to expand to expand
to a wider area
Then we are going to be the subject of this experiment
This is the dirty bug bought in Nepal
In fact, you can also think about it
If you can ignore moral issues today
you go to experiment say
going to test says
man can expand so fast
Does it have anything to do with forming a social group?
what experiment will you do
Of course, you may not have this habit
Then let's live and think about it
what is the best experiment
Then with this example, I would say
Actually if you can
I say now just assuming there is no moral question
You can actually say I'm looking for 100 people
then one pair
One male and one female can reproduce like this
then you force them
Just one pair
You send him to that equator to the North Pole
various places
This is where humans are now expanding
You just force them to be a couple like this
you have an independent society
the so-called lack of social groups
Solar theory
of
individual
Then of course another group of experimental groups
you might just say
Let's say I send 50 people to a place at a time
right
That is, you can look at these 50 people
just in different places
his chances of success
Of course this experiment is on people
it's impossible
so we can
But we can buy chapters in our
Do something like this from inside
that we can force them
only one pair
Let him have many individuals with one follow-up
and you send him to that
different ecological environments
Specifically
Of course, before introducing this experiment
Just to briefly introduce this chapter to everyone.
This is actually very common in Taiwan
In Nangang here in winter there will be
no more now
They are, as the name suggests
he will use the corpse
when he found the body
He actually has several
he is not a relative either
Mainly because this corpse is a changing environment
So when a dead body
Buy chapters from Wendai and Wendai
it will fly from all directions
And then they'll put the body together
get it in the soil
Then place an order near this soil
Then the cool part is to say
In fact, they can use their
This secreted chemical substance in the body
embalming this corpse
Then give them children to eat after abdominal disintegration
They also feed the children like this
So just say that
We actually want to understand this
Cooperative Behavior Social Behavior
The relationship with his ecological response
So we will manipulate his group size
Okay, so the way it works is
We just put two and six individuals
go into the wild
Of course the most challenging thing is to say
how are you out in the wild
is to control his group size
Then of course why in the wild?
Because of his ecological challenges
The main thing is that he competes with flies
when you have a dead body
Flies will come and take this soon
So what they are fighting against is you have to bury these corpses in the soil very quickly
That way the flies can't use it
Our different ecological gadgets are that we can
In the east-west section of neutralization we can follow the elevation
Then of course this is the Meifeng Farm that I just mentioned
this is where we live
So we can quickly go from very low to high to do research
Like here, the altitude may be about 1,000 or so
We can always do fast three thousand
So you can have different this environment
And of course we also need a lot of people to do field experiments
Then its biggest competitors for decomposing corpses are flies
sorry that's not very clear
That is to say, it is actually quite intuitive, that is, the hotter the fly is, the more competitive it is.
The reason is that flies can fly very quickly
The children of flies tend to decompose the corpse very quickly
This experiment is only difficult in one place
that means you're going to be out in the wild
Let the burying bug have no way to get in and out
So when we put two in and six in
it can sustain this expenditure
But there must be a way to eat and drink freely
compete with burial bugs
This is the most difficult part of designing this experiment.
my research statement
It took him a month
Suitable for dozens of combinations
finally developed a method
That means we use burial bugs and catering
The ability to fly is different
So we made another Wuyan
Then this is like this
just use that head video
Then stick a long black rock
with a short black rock
means to make a channel
It's the burial bug because it's bigger
It can fly without food
So you design a channel for something hard to fly
Let only catering can fly in
Mahjong Bug, we want to paint all over the top of this head video
Just let it go up and it will slide, so there is no way to climb forward
So the key to use is that you have to be very careful to paint this decorative forest evenly.
The bug is also very powerful, and sometimes it will make mistakes, that is, if it is not painted well, it will go in.
It looks like this
Of course, the result is that we can actually guess successfully.
Let's talk about the size of the worm group. This large group is about 5
It’s just that there will be less. If it doesn’t like it, we have designed a channel so that it can fly away.
But if there are two, occasionally there will still be very powerful insects outside that can come in.
But it's close to two so we can create this big group and small group we just talked about
Then you put along the altitude
You can see the impact of cooperation and this in different environments
Then you can see the result, of course if you don't see it very clearly
It means that the reproduction is successful. This is also the altitude.
This is temperature, this is reproductive success
Then the blue line is a pair of individuals
I just talked about two
The orange ones are the ones who just talked about this large group.
The one most important result is here
That is to say, in fact, large groups of individuals
Success Rates at Low Altitudes
is significantly higher than that of the two small groups
In that case, if you convert it into temperature, it means
In places where the temperature is high, the burial must cooperate.
The chances of success will be much higher
So in fact the result is that
In fact, the group is the scope of its distribution
Having enough range with them to breed is a big help
In addition, it is because just now
we want to record
so we can quantify them
just above the altitude
Conflicts with different temperatures
Well, the burial place is actually the place with the best environment.
It's a middle altitude place
they spend the most time fighting
Just put a lot of effort into fighting
Then what
As for the investment, this is a video of their fight
Of course, this was recorded in a laboratory, so it's a bit cleaner
I can't seem to let it go
It's ok, just fighting is what they bite
Then, in addition, we can look at his investment
That is to say, in fact, he took the time to talk about
Disposing of corpses, embalming, etc.
In fact, it was also at the time when the lowest Haiba was the lowest, and this group
The orange one is a group, the blue one is two, and this one is six
In fact, the lower the sea, the hotter the place
In fact, the group will spend more time
Let's dispose of this corpse together
So the result is
It can be seen that he actually
It's interesting to say
two
In fact, his success rate is higher in the middle Haiba, and for the six, his success rate is higher in the lower Haiba
That's actually because of this
Large groups can cooperate
Then drive the flies away at lower altitudes
That's why this result
good
What's more, it's for
Because we mainly do it at altitude
So that's because of the experiment
It's just that you want to make it clear
Is it the effect of temperature?
So our assistant designed a heating plate
when in the wild
That's a concrete resistor
Then we can put this body in this
above the heating plate
so you can
For example, at mid-altitude to heat a corpse
and see if it's this
It's really the temperature that affects their cooperative behavior.
what about this
This is heating and this is control
that does mean
The orange ones are large groups
The blue ones are small groups
just said
In fact, when doing this at mid-altitude
The reproductive success of two is actually higher than that of six
but what about after you heat
In fact, the success of six is ​​higher than that of two.
Then his investment is also heated
His investment is more than control is a large group of words
It is more investment
That's another, more experimental proof that
In fact, it is the effect of temperature
to influence his cooperative behavior
So let's sum up that
In fact, you take this picture to mean
The size and size of the fly represent the stress of the fly
The hotter the place, the higher the pressure of the fly
then buried as if you were two individuals
In fact, we have information
I'm just drawing pictures for everyone to see now
That is to say, he can only be in a warmer place
reproductive success
but through cooperation
He can actually breed it successfully in this range
expanded
So this you can see is that
In this example, it means
Cooperation can actually promote the expansion of his ecological niche
Then it's Mandarin and it's time to visit
there is a picture
That is to say, everyone is in a very fun environment at middle altitudes.
Everyone fights hard
But the low altitude because there are a lot of flies
So everyone will work hard together to dispose of the corpse.
Then we contributed at that time
A very interesting editor used this Social Insight and Climate Change
The difference is probably because we have to heat the dead body
When you can see it is like when it is hotter
In fact, you can see that organisms may become more cooperative in the face of harsh environments
So I didn’t go back to what I said at the beginning, what does this have to do with people?
So in fact, let's look at this social behavior of people.
Does it have anything to do with this extension?
In fact, I think the most important thing from what I just said is to say
In fact, what is the reason why people form social types?
In fact, what we need to know most
Of course, one of the main theories now is that in fact, there is competition among species.
That is to say, people are actually between tribes and tribes.
because of the war
So if you don't form groups
Then if someone forms a group you lose it
so you have to form groups
The other thing is to cooperate to take care of children.
Another reason that may be important
That is to say, in fact, if you want to talk about human children
In fact, the head is very big
So I was born when I was helpless
so many people to take care of it
Then what I put forward is called the Born of Misfortune Hypothesis
that is, why is this relevant?
That is, if this species
Evolved this cooperative behavior in harsh environments
to fight against this ecological environment
bad ecological environment
Their competitiveness can actually be strengthened through this cooperation
Well, it's actually at the species level
It will actually be more competitive
then we haven't done it yet
But it's interesting to say
Because we Nepali burial bugs
What we found is that it actually
its cooperative noncooperative behavior
is entirely affected by the presence or absence of flies
so but what
In fact, the history of burial bugs has been studied a lot
Their evolutionary origin is
This worm may have had his ancestors in
Probably China, a place in Mongolia
The oldest burial bugs evolved over there
But it's interesting to say that this burial bug we studied
In fact, it may be in this area
This is what evolved
Well, but his current distribution range is actually widely distributed in the whole of East Asia.
The funny thing is you think if he
If he evolved in a temperate zone
It might not be that sensitive to flies, actually.
So far apart from our
In fact, beyond the study of burial bugs
Burying bugs haven't seen similar behavior anywhere else.
So I don't have a hypothesis just to say
In fact, it can be measured
that is to say, is this
Our burial bugs actually evolved after the tropics
slowly expand back
it's a colder place
Because he can actually fight the heat
He can be in a cold place
Through cooperation he is
Species that can adapt to a wide range of ecological environments
So we can test whether his history is like this
Back to people, that is to say, in fact
There are other studies that say
That's because you can't do it directly
So let's study and compare different monkeys
Social monkeys and non-social monkeys
Or the relationship between group size and brain volume
Then you will usually see that it is actually possible that this brain capacity
species with larger groups
The higher the level of society
Brain capacity may be larger
That's only circumstantial evidence
The social brand is the head of the society
So this is also a way to say that you actually face this social challenge
then let your
May be stronger
Then you say that you are born with advantages and disadvantages
so you can
the species or population can become more successful
what about the end
Let me introduce you briefly
I just talked about social species
Now let's talk about this vertebrate marine animal
distributed
Of course this is my challenge
The classic theory of ecology actually challenges Darwin's theory
Probably very difficult, but what we're talking about is
the theory of ecology the theory of ecology
What are you mainly talking about? That is, because now
What about the relationship with global change, so a lot of research
Try to answer that in fact it is
The species with high tails are still tropical
species that are more vulnerable to warming
Of course, everyone can think about it
What do you think is the difference between the temperate zone and the tropical environment?
Generally speaking, it may be a place with high tail
Spring, summer, autumn and winter may be very clear, and the temperature in the tropics is very stable.
So what about ecology?
It's just a simple idea that actually
this is the species and then what
The gray line is the current temperature
X is temperature Temperate species
Because the temperature varies greatly throughout the year
So everyone thinks
That is, temperate species can adapt to changes in the seasons of the year
So it can tolerate the temperature range
wider than tropical species
Because the temperature in the tropics is very stable
So the temperature range they can adapt to is very narrow
Therefore, in the case of generalization, you increase a few degrees
No problem for temperate species
Because it can adapt to this changing temperature environment
But if a tropical species fits so narrowly
A few degrees more warming and they're in big trouble
So now everyone thinks that
In fact, this warming
Although it may be at a high degree
The warming of the physical environment is more serious
That is, the degree of warming will be higher at high altitudes
temperature will be higher
But on the contrary, it is the species that everyone thinks is called tropical
because the temperature is stable
So it is more affected by warming
High status is born of sorrow
because of the constant challenges
Then this probably died of peace
Because it is a very stable environment
So everyone thinks so
But in fact, we are because of the relationship between buying and storing
you start on the hill
It's the cooler temperature along the altitude
cold for a long time
Then you discover that in fact this
Of course you don't have to be cold
If you go to that mountain in Taiwan
you must feel it
That is to say, this is the month in the mountainous area.
this is the temperature
Then you can see that it is the soil of No. 2006
It is the so-called tropical low altitude that it can
with tropical mountains
you see its temperature change
Let's say it's 15 degrees
it's 18 degrees
the possible change is
Is it just a few degrees?
two or three degrees
Then they think this temperate zone is
very big change
It can be -20 degrees to 10 degrees
It is in line with what I just said, that the tropics are very stable.
Then the temperate zone changes a lot
is it true
This is actually the monthly average
If you have been to the mountains of Taiwan
You know, that is, the one on the mountain in Taiwan
For example, you go to summer
to river bend hill
It was very hot at noon
And at night it's actually very cold
It's not them, it's these tropical
when temperate researchers imagine
In fact, the tropics is a very stable environment
not like this
What about the evidence? Like this is actually a piece of evidence.
That is to say, this is what we measured in Taiwan
It is Taiwan's high-altitude open land
In fact, the temperature difference can be very large
It's 10 degrees at night
Then it can reach 20 degrees at about 12 o'clock in the daytime
10 degrees at night
Of course, the temperature difference is not so much different at low altitudes.
That means that in fact, when everyone was thinking about ecological phenomena,
In fact, they all focus on the changes in a year
but no one thinks about saying
In fact, the change of the day is still a change
So what exactly is the effect on the species?
So let's analyze this
It is this database that has been sorted out by someone.
It is the range of distribution of these species in the world
Then what about the distribution range in mountainous areas
So what we found is this
what everyone thinks
That is to say, the higher the tail
The larger the annual temperature difference, the larger the distribution range
Because it adapts to all seasons
This is no problem, indeed we have seen it in our analysis
But the interesting thing is to say
In fact, we found that the places where the daily temperature difference is greater
In fact, the distribution range of the species is smaller
That is to say, on the contrary, this time is a very bad environment.
It's a place with a big temperature difference
On the contrary, the distribution range of your species is very small
This is something no one has ever seen before
Of course we are the same
That is, we made a mathematical model to explain
Why is the long-term temperature difference different from the short-term temperature difference?
have the opposite effect
That is mainly a relatively simple idea that
If the seasons change throughout the year
Actually you can't escape
You must live all year round
But if it is a short-term change
In fact, it is more efficient
Changes in such a short time
Instead, you can choose the most suitable temperature for breeding
So look at the pattern
If you only look at the survival of the species there is no way to explain it
It's you who want to live through the four seasons of the year
You have to live through this day and night
But what about breeding?
In fact, you can compare specialized
just to act like a short time
You just breed in a more suitable environment.
so what
This instead means that deciding this is a matter of being born in peace and happiness.
That is to say, it is a better environment
The scope of its divisions can actually be wider
So in this case it is not necessarily
What everyone generally thinks is that this person is born in good times and dies in peace.
On the contrary, it is necessary to have a good environment because the difference is relatively small
Then this very important explanation is that
In fact, in addition to watching the survival of a species, you also have to watch its reproduction
then this is this
In fact, this sentence is very reasonable
The meaning of life is to create the life of the universe Jixi
Probably the most sensible sentence he ever said
Then what
So you can think of saying
When the temperature difference is short
you're like actually we can imagine that is to say
diurnal animals, nocturnal animals
diurnal, nocturnal
you are more focused on this
But when the annual temperature difference is large
In fact, you may just want to
That is, if you survive, you can survive as long as you want
Then we use a more careful mathematical model to prove that
Let's go back to what everyone cares about
the impact of climate change on organisms
Then this is born from optimized use, right?
In fact, we think it's only half true.
It might be like this when you go to see survival
So what everyone ignores is that
Just to see that the annual temperature difference is small
There's nothing wrong with the tropics being in danger
But places with large diurnal temperature differences
this green place
These green places all over the world are places with large diurnal temperature differences
On the contrary, it is now on the conservation
It's that people don't pay attention
that of course means
What about our so-called challenge to this classical theory of ecology?
Then even if it is published on Science
Then I said the reason for Yuku Wule
This article means that Science has found an expert in our field
introduce our articles
then you look at its title
Sano Travel in the Tropics
still talk
The tropics are the most vulnerable to warming so
Basically, he didn't understand what we were writing
He still does what he thinks, that's our biggest breakthrough
As a result, it was not written in his title
But no way, that's the way science is
Then, let's go back to the summary, that is, the examples are finished.
That is, everyone, I think that in my research
I think it's the most worthwhile place
That is to say, whether the environment is good or bad depends on its competitiveness
Whether it's the competitiveness of individuals, the competitiveness of species
Or what is the relationship between the competitiveness of the group
So, in other words, you can imagine
It must be, that is the flowers we are talking about
Seems like a negative word, right?
The flowers in Wen's must be bad
That's my one, just what I wanted to say
In fact, if you think intuitively
Like this example, this is what I took yesterday, and this is what I took today
Then, we have a pot of this potted plant on my balcony
The balcony outside the big company is amazing
I haven't watered for a long time
then these
this is in front of my desk
I water like this every day
Other activities will be very good
In fact, life is also quite powerful.
just give him some water
it will get better soon
So in fact, for most of life
actually good environment
Actually it would have made it better
right
that is
But I find it interesting to say
when is the best time
to species
For example, an individual or a species or a group
is better
when is bad environment
On the contrary, it is better
Then I think this problem is actually very
very common
Every aspect of our daily life
In fact, I have always encountered the same problem
that looks like
because i have two kids now
So I often think about this question
That is to say, things like education
that is
you want
like someone said
you have more money
You want to let the children live
Of course, a lot of it is just experience.
not really poor
But there are also studies
The second is American studies
That is to say, in fact, in the United States today
In fact, rich people's homes
is a very big advantage
Or families with higher social status
is more resources
And now it's getting harder and harder to turn over
So the environment is good or bad
with the impact of this education
I find it interesting to say
In this example
He said a very important reason for poor children
That is to say, it is actually an example of him fighting hard.
just hard work
then they go and say
In fact, these places are very poor because of the poor material conditions.
So the kid over there is actually
in a poor material condition
Instead, it becomes very cooperative
So of course it's very similar to what we see
That is to say, in fact, if you want to train children
If you are good at cooperating with others
Probably because you can't let him have everything.
There is no need to cooperate with others
But that doesn't mean
In fact, it is not good
This environment is always good
In fact, I think this example happens very often in Taiwanese society.
ok wait a minute
What about the other thing about global warming?
I think it's very relevant to our lobster example
That is to say, there are actually many elders here.
like i feel
When we were in college, I was in the guidance agency
At that time you talked about global warming
It seems that not many people care
and then at the government level or
In fact, there are not many people who put in real effort to do it at a higher level
Then I think it's like this lobster example
It is actually to let everyone do this public thing
That was, of course, the meeting in Paris last year.
Let's say we sign an agreement
How much do you want to reduce carbon?
is that finally there might be something more concrete
Then the U.S. may finally join in on this
Then I think the most obvious reason
That is to say, you can actually imagine
Humans on earth are a very large group
Internet chatting is something that, for example, 7 billion people have to face
So in this theory
The theory of the lobster just now is when Qun Yue was old
In fact, before the near destruction
just no one will act
so the most important therefore is what
Just to let everyone know how close you are to destruction
everyone hurry up
you know it won't work
So this is actually
So I say this very common example
that is
In fact, in a very bad time
People will try their best to solve it
Of course, whether this matter can be resolved
don't know yet
where the hell did we get up
Then additionally in the section of national competitiveness
I actually like reading history.
It's actually, of course it's just
it's just small talk
That is to say, in fact, you can see that there are many examples of
is a country
under great pressure
it starts with
Like the state of Qin in the Warring States Period
In fact, the reason for his change of law is that he is about to fail.
Everyone is going to attack him
So he started with this Shang Yang Reform
So he changed it very well like this
And then there's this selfish individual
There is no way to be more selfish than
because the ship is sinking
like that this
I just saw this dragon horse type recently
Japan during the Meiji Restoration
they are the same
At that time, there was a strong foreign country
The black ship is outside to let them open the port
So the shogunate at that time
It's finally gone
So they reformed very well afterwards
So it became very powerful
That of course means
I think it's worth thinking about
Why is Taiwan okay today
seems to be very
fight very hard
I think it's an interesting question
Of course I hope that means
like this speech
Just like what Lao Tzu said
Good and bad are actually related to each other
Maybe one day we will experience this
And then in the end I want to conclude by saying that
Actually, I think studying this creature
various social creatures in particular
Actually it's like maybe there are biology students here
In fact, we study the behavior of animals
partnership with them
or ecological adaptation
In fact, as we say, for example
medical research
In fact, you are mainly an experimental subject.
not human
maybe a mouse
filial mother
Probably Ecolyte like this
The main reason is that
Do we actually have a common evolutionary origin?
so many things
In fact, the mechanism is common
In terms of animal behavior
In fact, we can see that
We see all sorts of things that could be thieves
Strategies shaped for different environments
So actually we look at different species
we can learn many different
their way of coping with environmental stress
Finally, I would like to thank the members of my laboratory
and my collaborators
thank you all
Thank you so much for this very good presentation
insight into
There's a lot of philosophy in it
so we can come and ask him a lot of things
We are open to your questions
Is there any problem
come on behind this
please
Hello, teacher
The slideshow you're doing now just explained it
That's what you use to defend
Why from simple biological behavior
Observed Social Barrage
Human social behavior will be explained so frequently by everyone
or trying to explain human social behavior
Then if we adopt your defense
Then the question I want to ask is
how do we know what to say
It is acceptable to use Social Barology
not over explaining
Without overexaggerating human behavior
When did we cross this boundary
already too over
It has even become the previous Social Dollar
exactly the same situation
how do we tell ourselves
this is usable
How should we correctly understand Social Barology
Thanks
thanks for the question
This obviously has a lot to do with the history of our discipline
have a little understanding
Actually, I think this problem
Just like my teacher in America
he is studying that
Just came up with the ecological limit hypothesis
Then it's interesting that
He researched that this Lihou rich in Kenya
Then he studied things
In fact, the closed household will have foster parents
when one of the parents dies
what happens to children
He actually saw this in the biology
Then he discovered that the interesting thing to say is to say
that is, if there are foster parents
small children because they will have children together
kids will have kids next door
There are often situations where the parents are kicked out by the foster parents.
Which means he actually saw it on the creature
In fact, there may be times when this kind of step family
can increase family conflict
What you said about this is actually something that I think a friend in the United States went to
That is to say, after he discovered this example, he went to the seminar to give a lecture
After it was published, some sociologists wanted to say
Is there a similar situation in humans?
So they go and analyze people's data
It turns out that it is actually on people
In fact, it is almost the same
That is to say, the data
well that is to say
As a result, the United States is advocating this
To let everyone advocate how to raise
When the value of the family was valued, I actually found my teacher
Testify before Congress that this family is of great value.
irreplaceable
when can you use
I actually feel like I just said that stuff
that is to say actually
this is an idea
then you can imagine saying
it is a hypothesis
As for people, there are actually many times
you can go to test
That
I think the question is
If you haven't taken the test you can't take it for granted
this is on top of people
just the same
But you can say it's a logic or say a hypothesis is
to explain a lot of what you see
For example, I just said
This warming example
you go to see people
There are a lot of literature telling you that
Warming will actually increase human violence
There are a lot of literature
Then there was a special issue a few years ago
But I can tell you based on my research
will not only increase human violence
Because I see in the bio that means
The harsh environment has actually increased a lot
Biological Tendency to Cooperate
so i feel
My research has shown that these research people say
In fact, there is an Otterative explanation
Then they can test
But before testing
I dare not say that it must be true if it is above people.
So what I mean is
In fact, when you study many organisms
your imagination
You can imagine more
just not only
For example, what we see with our prejudices
come please
i ask thank you for your speech
very exciting
Then you mentioned the animal example
affected by the environment
You said the higher the temperature
Mr. Kun will cooperate more
Are there any examples of plants?
That is to say, the higher the temperature
How plants work together
or any other behavior of plants
In fact, we know that plants are also fire
affected by the environment
Thank you
actually a long time ago
Of course, because my plant room has been covered
I would have thought of researching
In fact, some people have studied
plants of course look
you look like it won't move
In fact, there is also a lot of competition among plants
most research
is that it invests in this leaf
root ratio
So you combine plants with other
It's when we're together
In fact it will have a research
That is to say, in fact, you separated
they can still feel
next to another entity
it will invest more in root competition
So actually these game theory ideas
actually on the plant
I don't think it can be used
It's already used
that's just not that detailed
Because they may only use the results to say
where do you invest more
so
Therefore, it should be a direction worthy of future research.
I ask for advice
This system you use with normal creatures
as Model System
when wanting to push it to people
have a big problem
No animal knows how to use a computer
no internet
these emerging things
Subverted many, many social behaviors
Trump may be approved today
Actually they are very similar
because they all use
a very
His group is a specific group
Trump he is
Because the mantra is low, these people who are poorly paid by white people
but unfortunately they also use the internet
So it's easy for them to call something
So their behavior is no longer biological
This is my opinion
Ke P won because of the Internet
So you don't feel that modern society
There are many things that may not work
traditional biological behavior to judge
Is there any reason
actually
But I'm being honest with you
That is to say, when you have more graduate students
You will feel that this person is different from emotion
rare
People are of course very special
human-like social organization
we are very social
But you said a lot of our behavior
In fact, I think it is very similar to what we see in life.
right
For example, my favorite example in class is to say
In fact, the difference between men and women
For example, yes... there are children
But this is to say that a lot of research is, for example, on the sexual behavior of men and women
The difference is actually very similar to the explanation above in life.
In fact, there are very simple explanations, such as why that
Sociology studies
In fact, what I find interesting is that people in sociology actually do these things.
For example, you go to dad and ask
If a girl asks a boy, would you like to go home with me, for example?
I said I have a glass of wine with these ratios
In fact, there are many men and women who are very different.
cultural things
Then I think one of the benefits of our study of biology is that
In fact, it can make you understand human beings better.
I'm not saying that all things are the same
But in fact, I think many things are the same
That's right, I'm from Kaohsiung
so i went to visit sun yat - sen university
There are many monkeys in the back mountain of Sun Yat-sen University
so they have a monkey expert
he explained to us
There are three groups of monkeys
one is on flat ground
will run to other people's houses
Some are in the middle of the mountain
some are on the mountain
but anyway
they also have groups
That group has Monkey King
I'm not here to grab your job today
But the monkey king
he has many wives
So he has little two little three little four little five
Because when little five and little four may not be taken care of
Just secretly go there with his subordinates
The monkey king will be very angry like a human
Same as yesterday's photo
Then he will kick that little five out
So people do behave like monkeys
Of course it's very close to us
it's already alike
so but have you seen other animals with similar ones
like you study many birds
I heard that the bird also had an affair, isn't that the case?
Yes, in fact, I have a student who is studying this crown and beautification
It's the ratio of his cheating
External pair ratio
In fact, it will also be affected by the ecological environment
In fact, they are when the environment is better
relatively strong
Really are
Recently going to post this
I'm not the one in the back seat
he's been doing this
that i'm sorry let me ask another question
the bird he said you said different bird
he is in the same grass right
Don't the rest of the eggs look alike?
how does he know which egg belongs to his little one
Yes, actually the most interesting part of this is that
he doesn't know he doesn't know
That is, but he knew he was Mr.
That is, from the results we can see that
In fact, it's the guy who's an asshole who will serve the bomb first.
So you just need to know that my husband is fucked, I will take the bomb first
It doesn’t matter which one, in fact, when a child pays more than others
Because of him, everyone is a child and doesn't know who belongs to whom.
So I just want my kids to be very competitive
In fact, he will eat more food like that.
So they, I don't think life is interesting, that is
Their solution to the problem is simple
Yes, but it can achieve the same effect
I have a few questions
Regarding the picture, you said it was OnePayer, right?
He lived together again during OnePayer
So in this case, will he have a situation where he will have a MixUp when he is suffering?
This is the first question
The second question is that we know that there are polygamists in all living things
some are monogamous
Is there any difference between these two forms for his survival?
Is polygamy easier to survive or monogamy
The third question is that I just thought of it because I studied at U
That U is also Mormon
when they came from the east
Many men are dead
As a result, they become polygamy
Then they stopped doing it because the federal government interfered
But in this situation, look at people from your biological point of view
Monogamy is better
It's better to be polygamous
That's especially the case where there are so many smart people in the Chinese Medicine Hospital
If this breed is monogamous
Isn't this a waste?
I want to look at it from a biological point of view
Is this an excellent breed
It should be to let him live more
this is dangerous
In fact, there are various aspects of this department of biology.
That's it
That is to say, it is actually human monogamy or polygamy
his is to say
If you actually look at the current society
That is to say, influenced by Western civilization
this society other than this tribe
In fact, there are many changes
Well, anthropologists actually did some research
It was found that one of the most important causes of influence is that
If your property is, say, land
farming you can accumulate a lot of property
or you are prologue you can have a lot of sheep
or those of cows
you can accumulate a lot of wealth
Then it will become a multi-episode like this
So for example if you were a hunter
You are a hunter, in fact, you will fight again
It may be difficult for you to hit too many
So at that time it will be closer to the first phase
So from our point of view it is
Of course it doesn't mean that culture doesn't matter
But there are actually some ecological factors
allows you to account for these variations
but you said
so-called good or bad
This is a very
I think it depends on whether your definition is good or not
What means
That is to say, from our point of view, we will feel that
It's actually hard to answer
This one-period or multiple-period
Or even like, say, Yunnan
This issue has multiple
In fact, there are reasons for it
That very important point is that
You have to look at it from an individual point of view
why is this the result
Because, for example, the reason for talking about the individual just now is to say
if i today
like a rich man
In fact, even in today's society
he is still polygamous
That's not really for the good of the group
He is for personal good
So the shaping of this pairing system
In fact, there is a conflict between the individual and the group.
Then he also from the perspective of a population
From the point of view of a group
There's a Big Reason Why We're Monogamous
that is
If polygamous
In fact, the natural phenomenon of this group is that
there will be many people without wives
So at this time, social problems will actually be very big.
Because of this conflict will become very high
That is, the conflict between the public will become very high
So maybe monogamy can reduce this
Just forcing everyone to do this
It is a way to reduce this conflict
What about Huamei
I just said that our
Because we have tested DNA, it has at least 70% of children
is the behavior of the pairing above
So for this example, they live so close
The proportion of European and foreign pairings is actually not high
In fact, most of the children are us
In human terms, it is called marriage and childbirth
you can tell they're a couple
Let's see him as a couple
He's actually going into pairs during the time he's mating
So we use that to define
It turned out that the DNA test was actually quite accurate.
So we test DNA with DNA
then i want to ask
then you talk about it first
thanks for the interesting talk
I want to ask
just a very interesting thing is the lobster
the way they attack
Then you mentioned that the group is relatively large
more difficult to decide
that i mean
I want to say will it
It is not actually a cause it is actually an effect
It means that you can't do well because you are better
it's up to you
Quicker decision, of course he left when he was still in a small group
Then he may be the more difficult individual for him to decide.
He'll just keep getting bigger and bigger
So he maybe he is a country not a battalion
then can you
But because this thing is the process he is going around
He is actually the collaborator. He actually went to see it.
So he's not saying that I'm getting bigger and bigger
Yes, there are a lot of them going around like this
In other words is it possible to have other quotes
For example, compare those decisions
I keep saying that assuming he is a country
Then he decided earlier that it might be them
For example, their genetic similarity is relatively close
so they can decide earlier
Oh, I'm gonna suck my life myself
Then the less he knows him, the less likely he is to get ahead
so he gets bigger and bigger
But perhaps to a certain extent they still
I don't know I just think
Yes because of course in this example it means
studying insects means
if you ask me what my burial or something
i can tell you
but when you go diving
In fact, doing field experiments is like this
It is the species studied in Vietnam
Like lobsters, we don't have that information.
That is to say, for example, we can't
Just kept drawing blood for research
So there are actually many possibilities
not so easy to play right
game theory if used
Actually those lobsters they're kind of selling flowers
have a look
In fact, the first person to go out said that he was the most timid
for saying i'm sorry
Then I'll hurry up, I'll run first
otherwise, right?
Foxes who are less afraid of death
stand there and go around
That's why everyone is hiding
let's see who goes first
Those who go first may be more timid.
Here's my halftime theory
Actually, of course I don't know about these
But that is to say, in the animal
the so-called timid and brave
In fact, it has been quantified a lot
This is also the individuality of animals in general.
That is, if you have cats and dogs
You know that animals are just like people
have different personalities
Well, this is the fact that many people have studied it in the past few years.
side issue is that
I've always wanted to go to Antarctica because of that research.
You know there are similar behaviors that are penguins
Antarctic penguins
If the vice president organizes a group in the future, he can go to Antarctica like this
So the penguins have a very special behavior
before they jump into the sea
Same thing, you don't know if your predators are in there
So they'll actually be waiting there too.
Then everyone should not be the first to jump like this
because you jumped first
easy to eat
But it's impossible not to jump off and eat forever
So it's actually similar
that you can go and say
Are different group sizes
Then when different feeding pressures
People who jump into the sea will be different
That penguin might be easier
you can go
It is better to watch more observations
Next to him is Nanjiwan
Thinking about transformation is like becoming a human on Earth
People from Earth City
Or the transformation and thinking that I am just a Taiwanese
It seems that if you change your consciousness at any time, you can change the size of the group you belong to
So what I'm curious about is that
it's true all animals
He only relies on his body
by his blood
Rely on his muscle group to divide the group
Or, in fact, there are animals that look like humans.
Just change the group when you think about transformation
Like saying it's supposed to be a spouse, he might be on
Did you join another group when you were a teacher?
Is the other group because of physiological
or willing or unwilling to accept them for psychospiritual reasons
Ask the teacher if he observes the animals and notices
Animal videos also seem to be able to show motion and change the group
Thanks
Of course the first one is like our burying bug
Although he is so small
their behavior is
I also think he is very flexible
We do various tests in the laboratory
You can let him choose whether you want 30 grams of meat or 40 grams of meat
Then when there are environmental challenges
He can do everything
You feel like you made the right decision
Then just talk about his social behavior
He cooperates and conflicts
You are the environment that is one degree worse or the fly is the
Of course we now know the mechanism
That means he actually has a smell on his body
He smells and he becomes very cooperative like this
That is to say, he actually
I feel better than we think I study animal behavior
The biggest feeling is that
Actually you don't know where their limit is
So what I just meant was
I think you can think about it
We feel many, many changes
And then many, many things are our free will like this
Then when you go to see Dongwu you also feel
he can do many things
and then especially
This very simple Togo can do many things
Well then you say, for example, his
We don't know his flexibility
that is to say individual
But you know that between individuals
there is still a big difference
So you know my question would be to say
how many people
Is it as free as we think?
that is
i'm skeptical sometimes
It's just that we didn't compare how to see it
Teacher, your question
Sociologists have to say people have no real freedom to choose
because he was influenced by his upbringing and his environment
so now
but you know what
I'm going to talk about this
I feel like the question of men and women is the best
It's like the difference between men and women
Talk about social restrictions
In fact, I think there are many not many yes
That's why all I'm going to say now is
The part that isn't
I think people want to say that men and women are equal
I really want to say that we are very free
But sometimes I feel like saying
It's like you just cover your eyes and say
These differences are not really
just so i mean like this
I have another question
you show that beautiful bird about beautiful bird
it's grass they come first
Then the second one squeezes it
Did you know that the size of the grass is fixed?
And if you compare
I said there is a grass that is slightly bigger
two go in together
Wouldn't it be better to raise it together?
i want to hear what you mean
I actually thought about this
That's right, why don't you make it bigger
But everyone knows it's just one
When this bird is about to hatch its eggs
There is a very basic principle
That is to say, the tree for hatching eggs needs one individual to be able to hatch
I mean you are a bird
That is to say, like a picture
We know its limit is about seven eggs
It's seven eggs lined up there
is a tree that a bird can heat
When there are eight, you can't heat all of them.
So the eggs actually hatch
The hatching quality will be very low
Well, we just haven't seen eight eggs hatch.
So it's actually useless to become bigger
of course
Said that Cao Bianda and the two hatched the eight eggs together
Isn't this very energetic?
In fact, this situation means
In terms of birds, they are called Separate nesting
is that it separates the grass
it only hatches
Then he separates
So you don't have to squeeze two people in the same slot anymore
Because it's troublesome, isn't it?
That is, he just formed two slots
Then, for example, my pair apply this
this pair put this
then when feeding the baby
You can feed everywhere
So in fact various
What I just said is that there are actually various types of living things
way of solving the problem
Why not in that point of view?
It's because we suspect
He actually just said that his success rate is very low
So set up this trough with the hatching eggs
the price is high
So if you put this price
I don't need to be together if we separate again
Because pre-division actually
no matter how many you feed
Each child still needs to eat a certain amount
So it's actually building a trough
Let's make a slot together
When hatching eggs, I apply three and five pills by myself.
probably not much worse
because he spends a lot of time
a lot of strength is
spent when he was going to fly out to eat
Then come back and apply like this
So we feel he has great interests
It's on this common trough and hatch
so he can lower
cost per reproduction
If it fails, it can start over faster.
here we have data
That is to say, after a large group of failures
it can start again in three days
Ask the teacher
so much of us from within
And the tens of thousands of species
Then why did the teacher treat the burial bug
especially come and study
It's better value for research
where thanks
Well, that's right.
That's the story simply told
Actually I started from college
I am a research bird, the research crown has a picture
Then actually after I came to America
After learning game theory
I think it's because of the birds
I didn't tell everyone
It's my manuscript that day
Originally voted for Science
Then what about Wei Yue's opinion?
It means that you are not manipulating your environment
Then everyone knows what I just said
What is the environment is rainfall
It's time for review
you didn't manipulate
no operation this rain
The amount of rain so you can't prove that it's all rain
Then what do you think I can do?
Which means I can't actually manipulate the rain gauge.
So I feel that if I say yes, I can’t do research. If people ask me, I can’t operate it.
So I just wanted to say I'm going to study insects
Many people who study theory study insects
And that's because I can experiment with whatever you ask me.
What about the burial bug? What makes him special is actually
Because many people have studied
From another country
So some basics
so i know he has social behavior like this
Then
There are many in Taiwan
so then
Originally, it was the choice between the burial bug and the wasp.
But because I feel in Taiwan
I don't want the tide I studied to be knocked out with stones.
So the Burying Worm doesn't really matter where he is
that is
it's more convenient
Mr. Sun, the host and all the audience
The question to ask is
we are at
Find the origin of a species
Also is what kind of method to find
Is it by way of intersection or already
Disc filling to distinguish
Thanks
good
like just said
Limber Buried Barrier
For example, where is his origin?
that's usually
It's actually kind of like that
For example, when we talk about human
For example, the Nandao Yuzu
where is this origin
A similar logic would say
to see where he originated
Maybe his diversity will be higher
so
that's a way
Of course, from this point of view
That is to say, you can actually use
use that
genomics of the genetic way
go back and say the same
Where is his variation higher?
Then you can read and say
The higher place may be
where he originated
because later he will
just fall apart
Are there any other questions?
So research biology is
quite useful
Interesting, I've seen a BBC one before
Studying off the coast of Milbren, Australia
It's underground, theirs, I don't know who is the Captain
Saw a bunch of crab shells on that bitch
It was later discovered that those crabs were originally on the bottom of the sea
At a certain point in time, like when the moon is full or something
All of a sudden it will gather and become a very large group
It turns out that they want to protect themselves, he wants to shed his shell, and change that shell
so all together it seems big
After finishing it, it will fall off within a day because the shell will harden
So that day is very dangerous, it will be cured by starfish or something
So there are really many interesting things in this
Like the lobster you just showed, I'm marching there
Very interesting, where is that?
I heard from the teacher of the Institute of Oceanography that Taiwan also has
Taiwan also has
OK
well don't know if not
Yes, I have
sorry i didn't see
come thank you
teacher ask
That is Crown and Beauty
is actually
Since if he fights for so long
His next generation of competition you will reduce if
Then why fight for so long
Will this behavior stay
won't be eliminated
I'll just talk
I thought this concept
no stranger to people
because we do this every day
right
more formal
That is to say, in fact, from the perspective of the game
In other words, the solution to the problem
not the most efficient way
It's the way others can't dress you
that is to say a lot
many things in the world
like say ok
Why do you take the exam
to read so many books
definitely not those books
how helpful it is to you
That is to say, you actually want to win
Others, that is to say, the logic is very simple.
In terms of Guanyi Chemical Media
That is to say, you want to say that if someone else lays an extra egg
If you don't give birth, you will lose an egg, right, so he will have more children
Only in this way will the genes be passed on, right?
What we call him is not a stable, it is not a stable strategy
so it becomes like this
So this is an individual behavior, not a group's behavior for the survival of the group.
That is to say, what we analyze today is most of the
Or most of the evolution is that you have to look at the probability of the gene being passed on
So it's all from an individual point of view
even from a genetic point of view
That's how it works
There is something wrong with this theory
Like our current economy is not good
So everyone dies
Logically speaking, I should have to give birth to more
Only children lose their temper
isn't it
Actually this question
is my favorite question
Because we're studying animals giving birth
In fact, if you analyze
that is
In fact, people say
That is to say, the one that actually gave birth to the most children
Usually, for example, your agricultural society
Those situations where you need a lot of manpower
But for example, if you are like Taiwan now
or like Europe
because in fact
Is it a challenge with the ecological environment
is the type
That is to say, the challenge between us as individuals
So in other words
This is rather difficult
That is to say, if you are today
Everyone farm hard
i can live
then live more
I can eat a little bigger
then give birth to more
but not now
if you are a child
many people may have children
That is, you have to invest a lot
then let him have
In fact, it is a relationship of competition
So biologically speaking
This very simple theory is that
Is it a matter of quantity or quality?
is the pressure to choose differently
when you are quality
will become like Taiwan now
It's hard to get everyone to have more children
By the way, just to tell everyone
Why is it important to study biology?
Like I read in the newspaper someone said
To solve the fat burning problem in Taiwan
I encourage everyone to be born like this earlier
I tell you it's the same logic
it's out of the question
Because I just said that if it is for the quality of the relationship
You can't have a baby earlier
so it's absolutely impossible
what can i do
Of course, if you are interested
very simply say
today's pressure
as just said
If you can't even afford a house
it's absolutely impossible
It must be like what I just said
you gotta stay home when ken is like that
So questions like these
if there is no way
this is not
so no easy answers
OK good
that time relationship
We temporarily thank Professor Shen
ok thank you all