can you turn it off first please turn it on for me please
Audience please wear masks at all times
And eating and drinking video and audio recording are prohibited
Do not use the flash when taking pictures
Thank you for your cooperation
Also in order to make our event better
Need your valuable opinion
Please scan the QR Code on your footprints before leaving
Fill in the online coupon
Help us to send the finished picture to the off-site service desk
After the staff confirms, you can get the exquisite etiquette
Thanks
good
you first
110 years of the Central Orchestra
Knowledge Response to the Five Majors began with the dean's popular science lecture
I would like to invite Vice President Liu Fudong to host for us
Hello, everyone from Cross-Strait City
Welcome and thank you for participating
Lecture by Dean Wu Dayu
Dean Wu Dayu Gu from 1983 to 1994
Tenure Governance and Science Education and Academic Administration
outstanding contribution
Committee commemorates President Wu Gu's 115-year-old
Min Dai held a special commemorative speech this year
Academician Liang Gengyi invited to our hospital
Academician Liang Gengyi was born in 1973
Graduated from the Department of Mathematics, National Tsing Hua University
Seattle after 1982
Ph.D. in Biostatistics at the University of Washington
then to
John Hopkins taught for 28 years
Returned to China in 2010
First served as the president of National Yang Ming University
The NIH director who took over in 2017
Zijing
The research of joint academicians has developed a new silver statistical method
Assist biomedicine and scientists to analyze genetic and
Competing Disease Epidemics and Data-Based Learning
He has an excellent article on Classroom Merchandise
He is studying in a classroom with his colleagues
Kumon published an article in 1986
Cited 20,000 times so far
won numerous awards
1987 was the Snetacore Award of the American Statistical Association
1990 Speakman Award from the American Academy of Public Health
2015 is the Carr Pillson Award for International Statistics
2020 in faith
UW's School of Public Health marks 50 years
Selected as one of the Change Maker alumni
year 2002
Elected as Academician of the Month in the Life Sciences Group
I knew him then
less than 50 years old
still around 50 years old
very young
Obtained in 2012
world
Elected as a member of the World Academy of Sciences
Obtained in 2015
Elected to the National Academy of Medicine
Actually, I know the words in Taiwan
Probably the two academicians
US National Academy of Medicine
ok let's go first
Warm applause to welcome the two academicians
Thanks
So if you don't mind, I just take off the mask
may be more clear
Can you hear me from behind?
sure
First of all, thank you, Vice President Liu, for your invitation and introduction.
It's an honor to be here today
Just mentioned this Dean Wu Dayou
I think everyone should probably be sick of him
understand to a certain extent
In my opinion it means
peak understanding of his tenure
Then when he Xie Ren, the two shows are breezy
his style
I think it can be said that we all have a style
So it is a great honor to be here today at a conference that bears his name.
inside a science lecture
Let me share with you some things that I have always cared about
let me tell you the outline first
I briefly describe my personal background
Just now Vice President Liu mentioned
Let me go from math to biostatistics in public health
go from left to right
Then the combination of public health and medicine
Finally I want to share
this years
My own views on medical education
do some things
but i think maybe you guys
Years of work at the National Institutes of Health
So you may also care about this
Future trends in our healthcare sector
personal opinion
Finally I know there are a lot of young people today
even high school
And some young scholars
I want to share with you
some of my personal views
The medical education I talked about today
i guess i'm not a doctor
So maybe if you guys think I want to start with
A disease his mechanism may disappoint
I look at it from an educational point of view
So I think whole person education
higher education
When Taiwan's medical educator university
So I want to cut in from these angles
I have loved counting since I was a child
So I think elementary school says
Just asked the principal to invite Mr. Rui to talk to us about new calculations
I found that I seemed to be able to answer them all.
also say these affirmations
good luck
I'll keep talking about this for a while
It's the teacher I met in elementary school, junior high school and high school
math teachers are good
Keeps me interested without scrubbing it off
It's actually easy to grind
But let me keep going
i feel very grateful
So my university went to the Department of Mathematics of Tsinghua University, where I was admitted.
Went abroad in 1977
First go to a small school in the south for a master's degree
I didn't do well in college
play hard
The only school that gave me a scholarship
Gajin doesn't allow me to pay for it
Then went to Seattle Washington University to study biostatistics
We are reading this bio summary and don't need to do Post-Arts yet
So I'm very lucky when I'm done
28 years before and after Johns Hopkins
Central China Exchange
In establishment 1987
about half a year
I noticed our Dali Hall
Actually I'm like a Renovation
used to be full of old
looks great now
There is also a year of lectures at the National Taiwan University School of Public Health
when the new School of Public Health broke away from the School of Medicine
At that time, I helped to become a program of biometrics
middle in state department
Associate Dean of Course for Three Years
Then retired in the US 12 years ago
Ex-principal at Yang Ming University
Then in December 2017
I've been at the State Department until now
math and science
When I was a child, I don't know if you have heard of
Mathematics is the mother of science
I've actually been listening to this since I was a kid
It may mean that our age is about the same generation
But I'll talk to him now when I get back
It seems that the old people have never heard of it
more senior
I don't want to say he doesn't want to encounter painful memories from the past
Even math is painful
no one admits
But in fact it is clear
In my opinion is a mathematics is the mother of science
I remember that our point doesn't seem to be very...
How about it
this car
So this is up and down too?
this is above
up and down
OK
i want to use this
good
Actually we are...
I remember that I majored in group theory in my sophomore year.
The depletion of junior repair
senior year geometry
In fact, it was very abstract at first
Learn more later
In fact, in many applications
Like group theory is basically
So the symmetry of a natural phenomenon
So it's in chemistry
I understand that he is explaining some of his phenomena
There is also the theory of detachment, which is basically a combination of set theory.
Understanding space, latitude, and the whole shift
Like this is a phenomenon explained by the theory of detachment
set of dimensions
Everyone has heard of Academician Yang Zhenning
What is the practicality of the physics he did?
Talking to Chen Xingsen who used to be in Berkeley
What Su Xue taught is the field of dimensional set
In fact, his field is very important to him
Explanation application in physics is a great help
And of course we are now like these years of COVID-19
We now have to look at the model we understand to make prediction
May be when will peak etc.
Like these are mathematical I think a lot of applications
Mathematics, I think since childhood, you have been saying
Then there is him one is black and white
This matter is yes or no
Welcome to the proof that we seem to define
if A then B nothing
so no room for negotiation
welcome is no uncertainty
It's a feature of mathematics
from its i think from the front
Mathematics is because logic is emphasized in the process
Logical thinking is very important
but to do things is to have principles
When this person is different
Should it be principled or flexible?
I personally think it is more inclined
Some have principles and some follow
might be more appropriate
This is my son Liang Chaogang
I'm going to talk about math
I made some to be a teacher
Middle and high school teacher also works as a professor
I want to emphasize this
It's not just math
Maintaining interest in any field is not easy
There are fields of interest
Not difficult
It's not easy to keep going
And it's so easy to lose interest
my old
He also liked mathematics since he was a child
I remember when I was a child
I help him with his homework at night
he is very new
he wrote
he is the answer
He didn't give it in the middle
inside his head
so i'm going to see say
if there is an answer later
if not the same
do it all over again
If he writes the process
we will discuss clearly
this is one of his traits
then to high school
American high school four years
So it's ninth grade ten years
in the first and second year
He went home with a total complaint
Said he was not interested in mathematics
He complained very deeply to the teacher
I don't think so
We are all two mothers and three thousand
we'll move over there
because the school is good
I think the teacher should be very good
Then one day suddenly
he brought home
the teacher said
He said our son plagiarized
we take this too seriously
we will meet him
also to understand
Later I learned that our children can talk
This teacher has actually
They maintained pre-calculus from the beginning of high school
This teacher no longer has this ability
So he has been reading from the book in class
or call them homework
If he is doing homework, he may see his paper and give the answer
He thinks his plagiarism
In fact, they'll know about his daughter herself.
There are also some racial discrimination in it
So then we do this interpretation
But what this tells us
The saddest thing for me is his grade
America uses ABC
I used to change A to C
I don't think so
it's that he's lost interest
This is the saddest thing for me
Then we will meet the teacher
They said he was originally from the United States
he's good
he won't let you say skip class
he is looking at your field
so he is good at math
maybe he's taller
At this time they said
You should go back to the front like this
then we will follow that
The leader of the mathematics team discussed with him
He said if you insist
let him say
you want to sign
Otherwise we are not responsible
we thought about it for a long time
my guy
We think we should let him continue
It turns out that level
In the end, I met that teacher in the last two years
very good
let him engage in interests
and not only that
how is his university
Also select those math
we asked him
What do you think of this teacher?
I don't know being a high school classmate
Or what about the old high school?
we speak
probably spoke in high school
nothing nice
he kept saying
he speaks in english
He said the teacher
He knows what he is talking about
This is actually a very high complement
so this happened to me
on one's own child
a teacher without
remember can make him lose interest
but a good teacher
what can he do
Re-realize
and inspire him
able to walk the field
So I guess this means
Passion for teaching is very very important
It is the influence of the Buddha world with or without eyes
it's a cause of conscience
The impact is far-reaching
I think this resonates with everyone
Later after going abroad
Go to the Operations Conference to the University of Washington in Seattle that kind of Biostatistics
at that time
This school for biostatistics should be one of the best places
Biostatistics is basically an instrumental science
We use a tool to help you to help the scientist
It basically takes complex data from where to what
Provided to life scientists to make a conclusion
This is simply like this
So what's the biometrics challenge like here?
have a certain degree of inaccuracy
How can it be inaccurate?
maybe because of something
We spend limited time
I hope to finish this research in a few years
So the sample size must not be enough
What if the sample size is not enough?
If someone else is doing the same, do 100
Sample 100 words
The result may be different
has its uncertainty
In addition, the measurement error
If we do epidemiological research like now
Measure blood pressure, general physical fitness, do 30
Because you see, the same time is actually very short
There is its Veration in it
And is the amount itself really good?
Like we are now looking at whether smoking is related to disease
For smoking, we ask you how many packs you smoke
this is not very inaccurate
That's how accurate it is
So you have to measure it out of your urine
how much do you really suck in
So this in itself also creates some inaccuracies
In addition, our scientific knowledge is still limited
Therefore, our conclusions may be challenged by others
So basically, so to face is to choose here
Then hopefully statistics can be used as a tool to assist scientists as well
Just to reduce the influence of this aspect on our conclusion
So we've all probably heard of the extra-mental space
So I'm going to watch this to know the height of the class
how many say i won't give you a number
I'll give you a space somewhere between this
So this is our statistical problem
Between biostatistics and mathematics
In fact, it was just a comparison
Just remembered I said that math emphasis is
no uncertainty
The stats don't
Without in certain, there will be no statistics
But what about the two
I think the statistical one is art
like we may be different collars
The same statistics may have different thinking
Do the same thing and see different interpretations
like a work of art
Maybe we look at it from another angle
So this same interpretation is not the same
But for us studying mathematics is our tool
as statistics are to scientists as a tool
So we have to make good use of statistics
I hope that some good tools will be developed
So biostatistics are important to human health
I want to be simple in twenty four seasons
I will list three points first
This may just more or less reflect
The research I am participating in is more
The first in the evaluation of new drugs
Benefits for patients with chronic diseases
Is it Efficacy
Then this is a field of statistics
Called survival analysis Survivor Analysis
This background is like this
Twenty four seasons I want to go through
After the end of the twenty-four seasons war
At that time the common people
Start off richer
So everyone eats well
A lot of food is more like the beginning of McDonald's
So many of these chronic diseases include cancer
Including that heart disease and so on
So a lot of new drugs happen
developed
So do clinical trials
Generally, if you often experiment
people with the same disease
Divide it into two groups at once, right?
One group was treated with a new drug
possible control group
Let's see if the new drug can live longer
sounds simple doesn't it
how many days does each live
Taking an average is the so-called T-Test
Maybe you have heard
where is the problem
The problem is that the disease
may live long
But I may within three years
like finishing this research
So within three years
how is he
alive
i know what
he lived at least three years, didn't he
then this may be longer
another thing maybe when i come in
probably left after a year
then i know he lived at least a year
like this so-called cancer
to shadow people
So this is becoming a
Survival analysis becomes a when
From 1950 to 1970 was a very red
Many doctoral dissertations come out of this
i want to show you
Here is an example
it's breast cancer
it is not a clinical laboratory
It means three different kinds of elegance
I want to know if it's some kind of elegance
it survives better
look like this
for example it looks like this
just a few months later
how likely is it to survive
Probably around 60%
used here
This is a so-called
Curtain Maier
this article
This article 1958
these two are totally on their own
do not recognize
self-developed
At the same time put that paper
review to this journal
As a result, the editor-in-chief of the journal will
combined into one
write an article out
is very classic
In other words
Just came out 30 years ago
There, a statistical method was developed
what is the theoretical basis
A group of statistical offices in the Nordics
to be found in the eighteenth century
At that time, some of the French
they are gambling words
There is a process called Possess
Stochastic process
How to predict the next step
That's called Modengill
The result can be used
So here is an example
Basic research is very important
You don't know when you will definitely need it
But what might the research you're doing now witness?
some new discoveries of yours
This is actually a very important concept
then back to the second
The disease is still unknown
Every medicine will still work
So everyone should understand
and it will be expensive
Is that from a prevention point of view?
Hope to find out the risk factor soon
can be prevented from happening
so this is an epidemic
risk factor
Then hope to be able to enter as soon as possible
For example, if you find that smoking is serious
Is that the way of guarding?
It is to encourage everyone not to smoke
Or already smoked this way
A health education so that everyone can quit smoking
Then how to find this risk factor
This epidemiological approach
an example of this
A practical example of this research done in France is
stone road cliff
Back then they had a hypothesis
The hypothesis is whether it has something to do with drinking and smoking
So this kind of smoking him
Drinking divides into two groups of people
Is this sick or not?
Divided into six groups of different ages
because what age might be like
getting older
This drink may be more
As we get older we also know
The risk to Shidaoya is relatively high
so he's basically a disruptor
So if you take this into account
This is relatively simple
but think about it now
Many diseases may have several risk sites
how to think about
So this in the 1970's era
is a very red field
this is main this is
Bressel and Day
this is my thesis
Professor Michinoshima
I'll mention him later
with a book they're writing
is a very classic book
The third is back in clinical trials
in 1980
That's when ez disease was discovered
Then do clinical trials
but it will take a long time
so at that time
There are many comparisons in ez disease
Relatively high knowledge
They went to the US FDA
to ask why it took so long
Why can it be faster
can make a decision
Do you want to pass
At that time also found
There is one in ez disease
Called BioMarker
biological indicator
It's in the blood pressure
CD4 anti
If your CD4 antibody keeps dropping
you're probably going to get ez disease
So think about it
My research may say
less than a year
blood drawn every two months
Your CD4 antibody
look at new drugs
Is it to reduce the speed you slow down
Like this is called Prinimposed Design
So now in Body
is very popular
This is a study I have participated in
This is with schizophrenia
It is a study related to visual debugging.
Everyone measured several times
See if it's a new drug
will make it the severity of the disease
can slow down
The main thing here is that Vice President Liu just mentioned
it's me and my colleagues
Articles in Huffman 1860
It is now becoming a regular use
This data analysis
OK
so these few
I want to give a few examples
Biological Education of the Twentieth Century
Actually plays a very important role
Assist scientists to be able to deal with some
I want to cover important health-related issues
this is for me
but i think about it
This is my first breakpoint in the production of drugs
Because at that time to study biometrics
just know
The love of mathematics does not need to give up
you can still like math
But it can be translated into human health
raised above attention
develop new tools
This is a way of no return for me
In fact, it doesn't matter if I remember back then
Biometrics is still the same
If the market is very red pharmaceutical factory
He wants you to be a root forest researcher
to develop new drugs together
he can't you do research
So he pays you more
school is already low
So absolutely sure that's what I'm trying to say
I am interested in research
So make a decision to stay in school
This is what I just said
Why did you measure it several times just now?
Why traditional methods cannot be used
Traditional statistical methods assume that
There is no correlation between the two data
I tell you this is blood pressure
Can you disassemble another blood pressure
you can't tear it apart
But if the same person is measured several times
The last time the amount was 140
take a guess next time you guess probably
You are going to 145 and 110
guess which one
140 for sure
Because of its so-called correlation
You can see that this is a very strong correlation
So this becomes a
Some new statistical methods
to deal with this problem
the one i just mentioned
In fact, the director of the three fields just now
he is involved
He is a
He's a biometric with this attitude
Pioneer
It's a pity to do charity in 2015
February 2016
At that time I was already in Yangming
in that play
Department of Biostatistics
Organized a Memorial for him
that day he said to do
Celebration of Norm's Life
He's No. 1 Norm
I go there to participate
I am from Special Central Taiwan to participate in
That day was a lot of his friends
his student
And family members are telling some of their old stories
many very touching
I found that I didn't know him well before
because he is famous
and he is serious
I don't usually dare to touch him.
But that time I knew a lot about him
in the process of coming back
I use me to lose
I have more than 3000 now
many facebook friends
Many of them are Yangming students
I just write him down
It's also a memorial
then a good friend of mine
He's on my show and he posted it
People's poems set people's faces
No random admission of students without meritorious service
poem doesn't have to precede address
address needn't be worse than poem
he said over there
Just how many of them that day
his friend said
This famous professor
You can imagine he must have taken a lot of students
no
He was between twenty and thirty years
Only accept about ten students
I am the fourth
Why
he will be very suspicious
He wants you to find the topic yourself
So most people don't dare to look for him
he won't say
able to overcharge students
can have more articles
he's not like that
he has a high
high standard
no merit
I did it with him then
Then I will find the topic myself
Then I will find the paper myself
come and see for yourself
But he also every week
discuss with me
But one day he found
he felt already
he can't go
He has no way to help in that field
He told me to talk to a teacher in the math department
go with him
Later, I was asking the internal teacher
The internal teachers are also very good
math teacher
it was summer vacation
he just told me
They don't see each other during summer vacation
this is my home phone number
call if you need
I will come the next day
so this kind
That is to say, this academic pursuit
care for students
I was a graduate
to follow
Back to me and our profile professor
follow him
I have an article written
I said I hope you will do it together
he said no
He said I didn't contribute much to you
He said you should find another
That was the original introduction
I told the guy
don't want
I because of you
You find an article very interesting
this style
Actually it affects me
pumping students after hopkins
I think I
Didn't help him
I just say
hang yourself
don't use me as a slogan
You can get more than one ackenagement
there is no need to suspect disciples
When I arrived in Hakeng
i just followed me
I just mentioned that article by Liu Puxiang
Our 1986 publication
Generally, this total article will be about thirteen years later
will slowly be affirmed
Turns out we were affirmed within four years
Then at the annual meeting
Invited to lecture for a day
we teach four lessons
half an hour per class
we two take turns talking
I was actually held in that hotel that day
More than a hundred people
early in the morning we went to the front
I look back
made the first row of water
professor
I was taken aback by this scene
The first one is our master
he came to listen
and the students are talking
remind me
This means to live and learn
The second is that he can't say
because i am a teacher
It seems to be listening to the students
seems to have no face
I think this is a
I think it's a very friendly demeanor
He told his friends that he likes to climb mountains
he has skis
He conquered the Matterhorn when he was 16
It's interesting to say that he went to the Department of Forestry at the beginning of his university
Later, I experimented with business
They have to climb a mountain to study math
Do you think this is a strange idea
If he is like this, he can climb to the top of the mountain and sit down and read a book
So he is a very special
then he is a leader
senior leadership
what are you talking about
After hearing him say that, he found
That colleague is always in the front according to his picture
he walks ahead
I'll think back to the inside of his office
He put a piece of paper on it
There is a leader who follows his path
he is totally one
So the research he did was very forward-looking.
You can see this should be very arrogant
no
Because he likes to climb mountains
he whole world
run to many places to climb mountains
So he talked a lot with the local residents
go to a lot of chat
to understand each other's culture
I will remember when I was reading to him
He talked to me about things in Taiwan
he is very focused
he's looking at you
very focused
he for anything
He therefore he is very humble
very respectful
It's a pity for me
when he was alive
no chance to learn more
I can't think of the next opportunity to share with you
From vital statistics to public health
what is public health
Public Health
I don't know what public health people think
Is it from the toilet and then wash your hands
It might be the idea that the comparison arises
In fact, public health is a field
A discipline is a maintenance
or really enter the field of health
What he emphasized
emphasize a few important
compared with medicine
The doctor is my responsibility
for my patients
best care
A certain group of public health officials
like a smoker
this group
Is he more dangerous?
so shall we do something
do some sanitation
to change his behavior
Therefore, in addition, public health emphasizes prevention
Hope to say sooner
can prevent him from getting this disease
In addition to that
After this time
I hope that some policies can be introduced
For example, after the health education
let the community inside
Everyone can quit smoking
so this is very important
public health emphasis
Inside the School of General Public Health
There are four main axes
Biostatistics and Epidemiology
Additional Health Policy
sanitation
but i remembered
I think the group is healthy
probably higher than public health
He remembered because of hygiene
will compare that
The concept of washing hands
actually because of health
more positive thinking
let me say this by the way
there are several nouns
public health international health and global health
The epidemic in recent years
I think you may have heard
global health matter
I actually think that global health and global health
is a trend in the future
what it emphasizes
Peer-to-peer care for each other rather than selfishness
In fact, public health, international health
This feeling of being private is
developed country
I'll take care of your undeveloped
Don't be weak and have no resources
I'm here to help you
actually not
some may occur in undeveloped countries
But because of what happened to them
If he provides the information
Let these worlds reciprocate
So it's an equivalence concept
so i'm going
I think it's called global health
this is the right idea
But back to this new crown pneumonia
I also saw one thing
even so
I don't know if you feel it
In fact, what is the weak difference?
still stand out
You are now seeing several vaccines being developed
how about a few rich countries
How much to buy at once
They have the money to hang on
countries like africa
finally they give them
For the one he probably didn't know about them either
The sanitation system is no way to do that
This vaccine can be distributed to various places
So in fact, I think there is still a long time
a long way to go
I will give a few examples now
public health
In fact, playing a very important role
Like it's COVID-19
This is the actual data
In this situation it should be 2010
How much in 2010
blue 2019
just how much it should be
109 to 108
what is this
You see this compared to the previous year
Has the number of patients with flu decreased?
because during the epidemic
In addition, the number of severe cases of influenza has also decreased a lot.
This is the number of outpatient visits
What is this because the pneumonia caused by the flu is reduced
how to explain
This flu has nothing to do with COVID-19, right?
But what do you all have in common?
wear mask
In fact, wearing a mask is actually because everyone sees
In fact, this will play a very important role from the perspective of prevention.
Not only so long virus
The long virus is almost like a child before the age of 15
It starts to rise almost every April and May
You look at this is the front this is 2020, 109 years
This is the average of the previous 5 years
what do you see
Does it keep going up until April and May?
The result is not up and down
what reason
when everyone kisses
including children
and thus get this
This and that long virus may be much less
However, their numbers in Singapore this year seem to be higher than usual.
Because the epidemic seems to be calming down now
because of negligence later
So many things still need to be
nothing is absolute
I will give another example
This is a study done at the State Department
Have you ever heard of lung cancer?
There is a drug called IRISA
Then ten years ago
They did a US study
how did you find out
The same person with lung cancer is not everyone
useful for this drug
Or find a mutation that may be related to a certain gene
It is related to EGFR
If that mutation is valid today
If it doesn't, it won't work
But the words of the United States
They just have this mutation and only 10 percent of it
As a result, our State Department research found that
In Taiwan, many of them are volitional
different culture
different races
We have almost 50% of the mutation
and there is this
He works without a suggester
So after this research develops
We'll go to the NHS for advice.
So then they changed their policy
Originally, this Erisis was the third line
or become tuned to the front line
Because it was found that for this virus
He helps these patients
So this is an example
is what we just said
The importance of public health groups is policy
Here is an example
Only current affairs can suggest a policy for the government
join the common people
but at the same time
This new drug is slowly emerging
what will happen
drug resistance
So we have a research institute for crude drugs
on the development of new fourth-generation drugs
so simply say
State Department Research We Do
In fact, a hope that can have a scientific effect
Can have social or policy effects
In addition, there is the effect of production and education
Here is an example
Well, I just talked about public health
make a brief introduction
I will talk about
That is, we are going to talk about medical education today
From my point of view, public health
My wish is that I never had any contact before
To the United States have a public health
then to medicine
This is Johns Hopkins' founding dean of the School of Public Health
Call Winnon Welch
He was the first dean of the School of Public Health for ten years
That name is School Hidging and Public Health
I'll give a simple explanation later
He used to be the dean of medicine
However, during the tenure of his dean, the dean of medicine discovered that
In fact, there are many diseases
use existing drugs
Still can't make him heal
So he went to Germany to learn
Come back and bring back the concept of prevention
So set up this academy
called Hidging
Hidging later this after I went over there
The teacher in the doctor is discussing
That means removing Hidging's name
Why
When I think of Hidging I think it's washing my hands
actually you might
look at that dictionary
In Germany by sea
yes there it is a
Science that maintains health
It is a very profound noun
when the former governor of new york
Mayor Michael Bloomberg
He donated a lot of money to the School of Public Health
Then the name was changed
It becomes Broomberg School
Pobby House
So this Haijin disappeared
Anyway
This is the founding dean
He founded the School of Public Health
Since 1916
Harworth is America's second 1923
Both public health schools are
Funding system of Rock Fair Foundation established
I'm going to talk about this
in 1970
There is a Pisper University professor
he wrote a book
He challenges the appropriateness of the medical-public-health dichotomy
Because there used to be only medical school, right?
Now pull out a school of public health
seems to become
This medical school is responsible for diagnosis and treatment
Prevention and governance of public health
He does his Challenge
He thinks the dichotomy shouldn't be done
I personally agree with his approach
This does not keep the public health students back
No, because I think it is very important for public health and hygiene to be taken seriously
But in the process, we should not look at this matter with a dichotomy
I want to give an example
It's a pity that he passed away not long ago
At this time we were in the United States as pediatricians for our two young children
If you live in the United States, you will see a pediatrician regularly for vaccinations when you are young.
or something
this one , he ' s a good example
I think healthcare workers should be on the front line of prevention
Rather than medical staff who are only responsible for the entire order and treatment
This is the second child, Tony Leung, he got married in May this year
What I'm trying to say is that the story I'm telling is about him
We had just moved to
Later it was the principle of that school
good school district
let's inquire
Just like this Dr. Michael May
to make an appointment with him
to meet him
we took two kids
That's five years older
The second child is just over a year old
that this one
don't forget the pediatrician
He saw our boss and asked him
you don't ride a bike
America is bigger
so everything is ok
just ride your bike outside
Our boss said yes
Then guess what he asked next
do you wear a helmet
I was still a little surprised
still stuck in the old concept
In fact, he is in practice proper health
he reminds you
you don't wear mouth push
Actually what he said
may be more effective than parental
After two or three years
one day
our second
he from the outside
play outside
he comes in
he has more than one foot
Our name is skateboard
Do you have
do you know that
that climbing board
he showed us
The front part of the helmet is so long and thick with a sunken
You can think about what's going on, it's obviously off balance, what about the head
hit that side of that place
If you think about it, if it didn't wear a helmet over there, it would be an injury
The influence of the family, and the entire society, may have to undergo surgery, which will have a great impact on the whole
But I think because of its relationship, it suggested that it has to do it
I think it's a physician don't forget, I think it can do a lot in prevention
It does another thing, and the same dick
How about when he was young we lived in two or three years old and I lived in him watching TV
Blink like that over there, we'll tell him to stop
He used it at that time, he said I can't help it, I can't help it
Later we heard the boss Bao Bao said that we went out together, and the two of them sat in the back
The boss heard his brother's side
because he can't control
So we heard a few words from him saying he can't help it
Let's go see this Dr. Michael May
After he listened to my name
say right away
What is it like to refer me to Halhus
This does Therese syndrome
This is a French doctor who invented it
This Discovery this new this
this syndrome
Then go see this Halhus
It is also well-known in the United States in this field.
Then he let us show him
After he listened to our description
He said right away he was Therese syndrome
Then he asked us this
one thing for our kids
He said when you were at school
He is about five or six years old
when you were at school
Did any of your classmates come and cancel you?
because it seems weird that you do this a lot
he said no
He said why did I ask
If there is, I will prescribe medicine for you
If you can, don't open it
if not we don't drive
We fell in love with him when he was in first grade
Let's talk to the instructor about his situation
help us pay attention
If a student has this situation
To let us know what we see is dealt with
So I put it here to say
This is actually called preventive medicine.
Pirrandian Medicine
what is the doctor doing
say prevention above
by talking to patients or
or the interaction of different people
able to play this preventive role
ok then i think
Next, let's go to the medical side
then i want to spend some time talking
past ten years or so
I see some of this myself
some things i thought about
and did something
roughly divided into these
Mainly talking about the 7 years and 4 months in Yangming
some of the things i do in medical education
I said in advance that I did not say
mechanism of a disease
I look at it from the perspective of holistic education
The first lecture is the explanation of medical education
this is
Bill Richardson he did it for five years
I've had four principals in the 28 years I've been there
all from outside
This is a field he does is
Public Policy Public Policy
After he became the principal, he formed a committee
Examining the Pros and Cons of Hopkins Medical Education
he himself is the chairman
Johns Hobkins School of Medicine in the United States
is part of the second school of public health
But he didn't say it because he thought it was the best
and how about going
think that means
just let him go like this
He also asked outsiders to come and inspect it for us.
what can be improved
He made a lot of conclusions
One of them I remember very clearly is that
One of the conclusions is that
The medical students he trained
Don't forget that America is a university
After the fourth year of school, after graduating from university
is a good course of treatment
but not a good course
Do you understand what this means?
That is to say, they may because they have enough knowledge
So think of the patient's origin as a what
an entity
One 11 Machines
To diagnose what disease a person needs
Instead of forgetting what his object is
is a human disease
I think what the patient sees
eye-to-eye interaction
It is this I to I contact that is actually very important
Make you feel sick
In fact, they feel that there is a lack of
so they made a decision
when they recruit students
Generally, students are recruited when masters
after they are students
they changed to junior
After junior accepts you
you are sure to come
When he was a master, he encouraged you to seek
many humanities courses
I hope to cultivate your humanistic quality
This is what they do
This has a certain degree of influence on me
his thinking
Before I talk about medical education, I want to talk about whole-person education
why say this
Because just talking about it in Taiwan is not an afterthought
So our medicine is also a university
Then our university now emphasizes whole-person education
So it's possible to do both
i think it's a challenge
What is holistic education
Today I talk about the meaning of university education
why is it important basically
It is equivalent to say that the transition from adolescent to adult
Or from being young and ignorant to being able to enter the society
Before this one, I think it is an important training
In fact, in addition to professional
Be a person and know how to live
Ability to lead and be led
In fact, the cultivation of ability is actually very ignorant of knowledge.
In fact, the cultivation of ability is actually the most important part of university.
That emphasizes that the scene is whole-person education and Listic Education
For example, I used to say that at Hopkins
We are all graduate students in public affairs
no university department
so we don't have a lot of contact
So I told my boss who is the one who likes mathematics very much
Everyone, take a look at the two of us. He is also at the University of Washington in Western Asia like me.
Later, I practiced the same degree in biostatistics only 30 years later.
Its just that everyone has noticed that my doctors castle is better than that one
It is because I decided to return to Taiwan to be the principal
I bought a very expensive one for this graduation ceremony
His rental is very thin
But I think I appreciate my older son
I think we've become very good friends now
I think he was the same age when he was growing up and he was much more mature than me
So at that time I wanted to know more about this holistic education
I'll discuss it with him
He studied mathematics for four years
He didn't do well in his first or second year because he was in the army in high school
He works very hard and gets good grades
He participated in many activities when he was a junior
In the society as the president of the society
Apply for that, apply for that Xiebo Proposal
Fight for funding
One of their activities is to go to Taiwan
The kind of parents and children like us
Huang Tang wants to run that night market
He writes Presentation like this
His grades have dropped
I'll talk to him
Do you think you will feel a little regretful
He will not
He thinks his experience is very important to me
Better grades than this school's leave course
I think that is more important
this first
Then when he was four years
he decided to go
At that time, what is now called the bubble economy
That is, financial investment is very popular
he wants to go into the field
But he didn't even study economics in college
nothing class
not repaired
I happened to be in Taiwan at that time
I'm in a bank when he comes back
do an intern
every day
But go over there and help pour tea
Help to set up the projector
then go back later
then he applies for a job
The one called capital one is for that credit card
That is to go to this field
go to interview
This was given to him
And he got a master's degree in mathematics in the same four years of university
Give him a salary of 50,000 for five years and give him 60,000
So we're going to discuss why people give you this
willing to invest in your
One I think after all the Happens school has a good reputation
Probably the students are not too bad
The second one is good at math
So he does some analysis inside
also make predictions
But I don't think it's the main thing
I think they also watch your interactions with people
Also, do you have the ability to acquire new knowledge?
I want him to share his college experience with him
I want to impress them with this aspect
So after I listened to him
I saw a so-called student education
bring out a direction
It's actually very helpful for me
I say that
Just mentioned the combination of medical education and university
because at the same time
So in the process
Medical education should emphasize that
Discussion on the Literacy of the Original Text
In the future, you still hope that soldier will grow from youth
Does he have the heart
and caring between people
I think it's all very important
When the other is to be able to find out
i want any field
We hope that students can find out their interests
bring out his former abilities
So I think these are the most important things in this university
is where we should be concerned
Then I'm talking about what I do
That is to say, everyone, if there are high school classmates here
think about it
If you go to study medicine
In fact, the field is very broad
he can do clinical work
The family will make up for the public
Because the desire for power for the patient
Medical Education Cultivates Excellent Stamina
It is also possible to engage in medical research and explore the universe for a salary
You can also work in health administration in this Ministry of Health and Welfare
be an administrator
The chief doctor and division can implement the policies of the members of the congregation
Of course, it can also improve the level of medical treatment in the biotechnology industry
So the road is very wide
a little bit below
Thanks
Have you heard of He Wenyong's name?
Have you ever heard of Luo Dayao's name?
Both of them studied medicine at university
One is Northern Medicine, the other is Chinese Medicine
What happened afterwards?
Because they are writers, because they are musicians
I see these medical students are very good
many talents, one is
Take a year off to study drama
I want to encourage them to go down this path
It's important that they keep their interest
Back to this point, no matter what field
I think a few key concepts
To save the motor, we must put the basic
call it up
The second is to say
We want schools to guide them
Let their interest go out even more
find the interest to go inside
So in my first year
Yangming City was established in 1975
I think it was because
The birth of the National Defense Medical College and Beirong
can be established
In my first year there, in addition to familiarizing myself with the environment
Because I looked at each other before
Very very unfamiliar with Yang Misi
Also in order to prepare for the application for the five-year 50 billion plan
I mainly did two things
The first one is PPL
PPLProblem-based learning
This is very common in medical education
Expansion of the content of the case
Reorganization of Second Foundation Course Confirmation
I put it on
PPL course is basically a small class
Beginning with Harvard University in the United States
Their small class starts from the third grade and the fourth grade
about ten people
what about them every time
It is based on the organ
not a disease
it could be the lungs
or the kidneys
Organ as the main axis
every semester
they have eight to eleven cases
Let's discuss each case
after discussion
be able to learn more about the situation
then i noticed at that time
I didn't know these before
I think they emphasize the mechanism of healing
Diagnosis and Treatment
it's all important
But I think they overlooked something
prevention
In fact, in terms of training the computer
They were trained to collect literature
oral presentation skills
because of this increase
But I don't think they
Put all the precautions in
So I was at that time
The Institute of Public Health speaks
so they spent a year
Atmospheric discussion about what happened next
put this lesson plan inside
just add this
plus prevention
And there are students involved
i think so
The whole is more complete
So I feel very happy
I want to talk about Yang Ming
then there are other opportunities
Go to Yangming and talk about my major
So there's a chance this can be used
basic course planning
Foundation Course
Even if it should be the most defensive MENTAL
should be the most basic
So then I was in the first year
Take time with that time to be responsible
A Highlander Dean of Foundation Studies
and the provost
In fact, Xu Wanzhi is the provost
let's discuss
Let's first set out what is the basic course
It is mathematics, physics, chemistry, biology and information
Then we set a few principles
course
Should be a small team
Don't forget that there are more than 100 people
that small team
In addition, if you teach this physics
Should be a physical PSD deal
like my college math
But I don't think I can teach crisis points anymore.
because i've been away for too long
I don't understand some of its flavors
so be professional
Then additional advanced courses
I think young people need to be challenged
There are options that need to be able to be challenged
There are many students in it
High school may have taken the crisis score
what he needs
advanced to accept his challenge
In addition, I think
There should be experienced teachers
Because basic courses like this
It's so easy to lose interest
to keep you interested
Even more difficult to generate interest
So we set these principles
Then follow along to teach
like physical words
we have photoelectric lock
and this volunteer
So many teachers are physics PSD
chemistry not to mention biochemistry
they are also
that math
Our Yangming Medical University has no Faculty of Science and no Faculty of Engineering
So then we asked
I found out that Central University is also very good at teaching
We asked him to teach the wiki score for the medical department
Later I found out that I was a school girl in Tsinghua University
Dean of Faculty of Science in Tobu
I heard that he is very interesting about education
I'll ask him to be the one who unblocks the Wikipedia
I share this story with you
he is willing to come
He said that because of his general words
You can work part-time for four hours a week
But because he can only work as an administrator for two hours
But he insisted that a moment should be three credits
I totally agree
But he only took two credits for this
the terminal fee
Yes, he insisted on three credits.
then he will say
I probably won't be able to teach in my second term.
But let me introduce you to a junior to pick me up
So a year later I asked both of them
Thank them on the one hand and listen to their thoughts on the other hand
This is my school girl Zhu Qiping
He told me that I had already taught his junior not to come
I want to continue teaching
Why
He's combining Wikipedia with the current book of modern times
He said I think I can pay more
There can be a lot of room for improvement
You know it's a good teacher when you hear it
He didn't come here to hang out
what he demands of himself
The second one, he said to see the student's remark
Then looked at the students
Of course, there may be some things that have been said and heard
maybe head down
Raise your head when you talk about something new
That kind of longing for new knowledge
Your current teacher must be very
He said I will continue to pay
i said no problem
Then your student can come
Other departments can also submit
The result of these two classes
The evaluation of the medical department
one year is the first
one is the first one is the third
So I use this to talk to that medical teacher
don't use this excuse to say
These are my benchmark classes
he is not interested
no
In fact, did you pay well?
you pay well
they will be interested in learning
is really very important
I'm going to talk to some students in the process
Medical students and medical teachers to explain
In the future, our students will be trained as outpatients.
Why should I learn Vicky Finn
I'm going to explain to them I mean the first
Wikifin mathematics is to train you to analyze
The ability to logic is a good way
i think no matter what
I wonder if I have the ability
It's actually very helpful to you
The second is also the ability to acquire new knowledge
His basis may be to show that you are for you
You have the ability to acquire new knowledge
Thirdly, I said that some of the medical department may study medical engineering in the future
Department of Medical Engineering at Haltor University
He taught Lemon Math
so i think we did it for a reason
Later I thought that I also convinced many
The heads of other departments are all willing to accept this matter
Simultaneous education
Going back to what I just said about Dean Harto
Shaw long Bue Richardson what they do
I think it's humanistic
So I also spent a lot of time understanding
what a general education course basically is
because i see it as a
It is possible to broaden horizons through this upbringing
and the way of dialogue with people
I think a cornerstone of whole person education
I think it's very, very important
When I was in my third or tenth year
I'm starting to worry about things
I think it should be changed to three credits
Two credits are not enough
It's the Qing court ordering water
There is no way to show in-depth
I think it's three credits
Give the opportunity to be a middle school student that learns
Cultivate a concept of secondary school learning
a legitimate interest in this
so it may take more time in the future
invest in this
Might be a Hobby too
So at that time, I and a dozen of my medical arts classmates
Discuss that they agree
Students, their classes are very heavy
they agree
Then I told the dean of life
Because the senior teachers are also very supportive
So at the beginning, I said to teach two courses first.
The result is not half done
I'll explain to you later why it's not half done
But my personality I am
Do not give up
Let's share with others what we do
when to understand the problem
The first thing we do is
That's the National Science Council
The chairperson at that time was Zhu Jingyi
He is also the vice president of Zhongyuan
He is very familiar with Dean Wen Qiwu
He convinced Dean Wen Qiwu
That is to say, the Central Plains Institute
I want Central Plains Humanities
The institute decides
In fact, the words of the Central Plains
In fact, university education
many places to invest
so they just agree
he helped us in congress
Get a research proposal
There are very few such training universities
NSC research projects
with this
Twenty researchers
with special researcher
Some academicians opened
The second course
They don't have a second class
It's a second class
we have teaching assistants to assist them
Then what
Let us learn to open six doors
colleague's course
that's when we made a decision
We also arrange cross-examination for students to come to the House of Representatives
It's not the easiest way for a teacher to come to our side
We want students to come to the House
This is the highest academic hall in the country
Let them feel the atmosphere of the House of Representatives
And it should be Lianjin Publishing House at that time
He also said that he hopes to publish textbooks
teacher if textbook
Think about education
there really are no good textbooks
So this is a thing we did
I think it's a very meaningful thing
come back here and talk
Why did I just say that pushing the three studies failed?
Because I know Yangming's department
There are many departments
They are all certificates
If you get a certificate, you must do an internship
So the practice class is very important
Caused exclusion of general education and basic courses
In fact, at that time, some schools said
one day and a half a week
You want to be empty, you can't line up that other
must be general knowledge
How do I see it
those teachers are sneaking away
just plug this
So the general education class time becomes much less
So at that time we said to open two courses
two classes
what is three credits
The third, fourth and fifth quarters are the fifth quarter noon
or seven eight nine
just what is that
And finally another class
It's actually hard to do that
so what then
understand the problem in this place
and hours
Are there too many classes in this period?
I asked them that they were actually Mando
but i will understand
kind of like nursing
some of their other private schools
It was during this period that he was able to tell his parents
I want to collect your tuition fee
is it really necessary
not too late
I remember at that time I was talking to a member of the Examination Institute
This examiner is Hu Yupu
he also cares
He especially once they went on a date
Went to Yangming to discuss
I also understand the key
professional association
They just insist on that many hours
just above this period
so what do we do then
I will discuss with President Xi
We promote the consistent concept of four plus one five years
If it is five years, you can have a double degree
Just have a master's degree
In this case, more than one year
can reduce crowding
Then we also know the students
we all our school
what we should do propose different options
give him a chance to choose
So we see that there are three different tracks
He will probably be willing to go clinical
Because it may be going round
or walk in the health administration's
So three different tracks have different courses
So we make arrangements for this
but said a restriction
Guys, maybe I didn't know at the time
The university law says that your knowledge can directly advance to a Ph.D.
this is allowed
Masters can go directly to Ph.D.
But knowledge cannot lead directly to a master's degree
So this is stuck in
so i can't say when you come in
let me tell you how
I just said yes after four years of training
Come back after you graduate and finish your fifth year
Then I went to talk to the Minister of Education
Hope to change university law
I just left after that
no more
This means I think
we use this way to change
In fact there are several
just a pharmacy
In foreign countries it is four plus two
this is better
In six years, I think there will be no crowding out
for technical courses
exclusion from concurrent courses
Let's talk about the importance of talent development
In fact, from a medical background
Actually working as a doctor in a hospital
There are also great advantages
Why
because he does clinical
He can interact with patients
he can look inside
There are some scientific hypotheses
there's nothing we can do
we are in the office
I didn't come into contact with patients
If there is no one like him, you can identify some
Some hypocysis that may be important
because you want to do clinical
To be researched, to be patient
Then he is a doctor, what can he do?
to persuade patients to participate
So it's actually a medical background
It is very important for flushing
When I was in Yangming, I was a labor student
So after you read it, you have to come
Six year construction cost
So after reading, after working hard
It's almost thirty years old
So later, at that time, I seldom went abroad to study
Then the wages stopped
So we want to say that they should be encouraged
Able to walk Bunong Road
even go abroad to give birth
so thank you so much
a kind person
You may have heard of Mr. Yanliang
he is very
a very different philanthropist
He donated 440 million
more than ten years
For clinicians in Beirong
With Yang Ming's medical students
so that they can go abroad for a short time
two months
In the laboratory of a top university
go for an internship , or do a trainee here
I happened to be at Washington University at the time
We have arranged for four places
It is very difficult to let them go
after they go back
they share
since they came back
they don't complain anymore
I used to feel very hard
go over there and see them
those same medical students
They worked hard, please read Paper
Let's read an article this week
He reads seven articles a week
and discuss it early
i want this for them
is an extension of the entire field of view is helpful
In addition, the long-term term is MD PhD
We are called Hybrid
MD is Yangming
But his Percis in Hopkins
We can provide another five years
2 million per year
let him go out
So now there are many students
Because it's here to practice Percis
because i see many students
is really very interested in research
Maybe the relationship between his parents wants him to go
Going to medical school will be fine in the future
Faculty of medicine can see in the future
In fact, he said in his heart that it was research
I think we've given the opportunity
let him go this way
so i'm going to say
school whether university high school
When we work, we must provide opportunities and challenges
let them take up the challenge
and then let them put their money to work
i did one thing
It's the principal Yuan Yue
We live in the principal's dormitory
that living room is big
At that time, we first went to see them and said
Do you want to separate it to make a suitable
we say no
i want to say
Hope to be with my classmates every month
Our class is far away from the principal
the last friday of every month
Students register online
go eat and chat with them
I want to know more about them from the inside
I also want them to think about some
They may have our own experience abroad
share with them
I am very grateful that my wife is willing to participate together
We also because of engaging with students
we feel
I feel younger too
because with young people
So we will be here in the past or seven years
we special fifty times
from six o'clock in the evening
sometimes it talks about twelve o'clock
Some students are still unsure
Very
very easy to talk to
i think the second time
One student left first
I'm already desperate for this school.
now it seems that means
what do they want
would you like to listen
He also knows what they say
we may not hit
but you are willing to listen
this is what they want
And for me it's also learning from each other
These young people are really good
I think I can learn a lot from them
And we I want to speak as a
is to solve the problem together
It's not about you and us
I said I don't like listening to your jokes
no we are one big family
Let's solve problems together
I will do a logic here
It is we who are bound to learn from the light
Then if the teachers in our own school
including the principal
not to make him feel that you care about them
How do you learn to care for your own patients from them?
So I think our Yangming's actually
Now it should be Yangming Jiaotong University
I was still Yangming
so i got used to calling it
Yang Ming's Mentor Production Department did a really good job
then i didn't participate
But I use this way
I use this interaction between principals and students
i just say by the way
I think I saw the old man talking to young people
In fact, mentors and luggage IQ are very important
they all need this
Now this entire video expansion tube
Then there are many choices, but sometimes you will be confused
need us to care about them
I think this part is actually very important to me.
I have a lot of stories to share with you
I want to talk about
Today at National Taiwan University
Of course this administrative job
I want to share a few thoughts I saw
The first one is medical and neutral universities
I'll talk about why I said it later
In fact, in the United States or Europe
A good neutral university
is good medicine is a positive correlation
like harvard on the east coast
Harpkins Yale West Denver
Duke of the East China Sea and the University of Washington
they both have medical schools
So to improve SCI
Then follow the high ranking
Actually this was in 2010
Mainland China does this
This is a combination of swarm universities and medical universities
Combination of Peking University and Beijing Medical University
become a university
That's mainly to say that it looks like this
Because the medical ranking score SCI is relatively high
This allows for ranking comparisons
Then I think this is entirely caused by the cause and effect
not for this reason
but because medicine can play
Much like a bridging or bridging role
It can be set up with different people
engineering management mathematics
Let's take an example
medical humanities
medical engineering
hospital management
biochemistry etc.
In fact, medicine can play
very important role
So I think a Chinese Arts University
able to lift up
this is very important
I will tell you this is what you have seen recently
That is to say, how many universities
Including Xinhua University
is my alma mater
The medicine they established
I know the medical community is very sensitive to this
have different voices
think they are from this
buckle his point of view
But I don't look at it from this angle
i am from a university
Because if China Camp University can go up
I have medical school that will play a big role
So I really support them in establishing this medical school.
The Department of Medicine should be the Department of Post-Medical Medicine
The myth of the research university
What about research universities?
It is a mission that focuses on cultivating research talents
It emphasizes knowledge discovery
Unlike other universities in general are called
Knowledge transmission is provided to students
In fact, with American personnel
America's major Harvard
Princeton was originally following the British system
It is knowledge transmission
Founded in 191876 at Harp Kern
At this time, they sent a group to Germany to learn Buddhist scriptures.
They are studying the German model is knowledge discovery
So it is the first research university in the United States
this book is that
Vice President of Columbia University
what he writes is what he tells
A look at the impact of research universities on the United States
found that in fact
Improve human health
quality of life with great attention
possible school studies
After industrial integration
to the whole health
such as health insurance
That Health System
wait there are new drugs
Actually plays a very important role
OK
I'm going to say that
research university
as the main field
But this is different from the general university education.
objects are different
A Holistic Education and Professional Education
the two are different
it takes time
i will say it
I see domestic
Many of our research universities now
even use this excuse all the time
I am a graduate university says
I just do research
so teaching is secondary
It's definitely an excuse
I think it's completely a matter of cause and effect
research-based education
The counter-responsibility of education is heavier
because at that time
School education Talents cultivated
The purpose is different from the purpose of the talents cultivated by the research institute
So that means you should put more effort into it
I was in Hawkins for 28 years
America's No. 1 Research University
i never felt say
We are a research university so teaching is not important
we need to spend a lot of energy
I am in charge of Gradure Program Director
A new course designed with a lot of effort
To train well and attract good students
In this regard, I think that in our country
I think there are still many places that need to be reviewed.
The third is the opinion of the guests of Taiwan Higher Education
This is my personal opinion, just listen to it
I want everyone to talk about the challenges of higher education in Taiwan
I think it's natural to think of declining birth rate
Too many universities, not enough money
It's not easy to recruit and follow, it's a fact
But I think the more important question
It should be more than this
I think it's false equality
Everyone has the funds for military battles
In fact, many things are not false equality
That false equality is instead a
everyone lost
In addition to that
In fact, there are so many schools in Taiwan
In fact, there are three different
One research type and one technical type
one is teaching
Like Feng Jia, Donghai, Dongwu, etc.
They cultivate different talents
Cultivation is the middle element of society
You are the so-called Libro in the United States
It's actually different
I think before
There are different research funding
Because their missions are different
There are different research mechanisms
Different indicators are right
Then about seven or eight years ago
get this deep root plan
I think it becomes a big pot of rice
break it all up
I think this is a very wrong idea
then we went for it
Later, at that time, we talked about research-type
these three words
Or top universities can't use it
because it hurts other people's feelings
I think it's a false fair idea
an attitude of
Also I think it's the whole process
Many do not have very long-term plans
first aid
did not think carefully
Just put out a policy
Of course, I also think it is very important
It is the maintenance of the University's autonomy
A few years ago, I saw that National Taiwan University was elected
I think that's pretty clear
is to see a political intervention
Recently, National Taiwan University plagiarized
So I think
i see it
They held at least this time
Just be sure to be the media
what that or the official
Various people say they are holding on
things to do
maintenance of the maintenance
I think this is actually a very, very important thing
ok finally i want to talk
our heterotopic domain
some future trends
I want to make two points
One is precision health and well-being for the whole people
A remote and smart medical care
This may have something to do with all of you to a certain extent.
general health
The scene means that now we see not only Taiwan
This trend exists in many countries
Reasons for a super-aged society
Chronic diseases trigger continuous growth of health insurance benefits
right now we
I think it was our ten or twenty years ago
The so-called 400 billion is now 800 billion
birth rate continues to decline
This means you look at it
2010 2023
This one in Taiwan is male and female
what about people over sixty five
increase in agglomeration
It has now reached this has been more than sixteen
percent in 2025
The likely prediction is 20 percent
That's the so-called super-aged society
What do you guys see?
Ten years after 2008 2018
Our Taiwan Mortality
Cancer Remains High
what is the second
Cardiovascular
Hadids
If you look at cancer
He can be said to be twenty-eight
Twenty-eight two percent of the past lives are cancer
And what about health insurance payments?
that's not one sixth
Taiwan's birth rate has been falling
From 1995 to now
At that time, there were 15 out of 1000
Reality becomes 7.7
not only
this is more exciting
how have we started
Deputy growth
It was last year. How has it been since the year before?
The number of deaths and the number of births have crossed
The number of births is lower than the number of deaths
I just said this
so already started
This is the death toll
with that number of births
what about this
This means that
Decreasing birth rate and aging population are more obvious
So maybe by that 2070
so the han award is early
Actually it's not that early
what about that time
young adults may be in
so mirage so an old man
may not be enough people to go
It's his problem to raise
so this is us
I want to confront him with serious questions
i don't think i have time today
I just want to say that our countrymen
Doing a Wei Fu think tank
we propose the idea
Precision Health
not just medical
medicine machine is a piece
this is all soul
From child to adult to adult
prevent from that
really preventive diagnosis
Early diagnosis, treatment and care
With this Digital Health
with different high-tech
There are also different fields
may be at home
may also be at the clinic
or a different hospital
How do I hope to provide
more precise care
here is a talk
if you start earlier now
how can i
His medical cost will drop
The later the start, the easier it is to rise
Also not
do it later
The likelihood of this incurable disease also increases
So I think this emphasizes this concept of prevention
and how
the sooner you start the better
Future Trends
I think long-distance and smart medical care are a piece
the cause and effect
I think it's because Chen Xiang gap is a
The doctor did not check
The Chen Xiang gap in Taiwan is actually quite large.
still a serious matter
Of course, with the development of high technology
And so even that COVID-19
this zero touch
For example, my doctor doesn't want to interact with patients.
an extension of the concept
So there is this distance and wisdom
from this side
So shorten the Chen Xiang gap
Accurate and personalized medical care can be implemented
Can reduce the risk of infection
But I think many things are two sides of the same coin
I think we're saying don't forget
Will this be the loss of this soldier game?
I guess I don't know if you guys say
I'm going to see a doctor and if I talk to him
This face to face he and I are very
very common tell me
I might be better off with a doctor
I don't think this kind of atmosphere can be replaced in a long distance
As I just said I do I contact
And if you are not careful, what will happen to cause the gap between rich and poor to widen?
Because these rely on a lot of high-tech words
We prefer whether the local area already has the capability of 5G
So many things are two sides of the same coin
this is an example
What our State Council recommends is that there are still Miaoli and Taitung in South Australia.
What are the first two points?
Yes, that old man is also good
What kind of sickness did you go to the health center?
And then maybe by Bidong Medical Center
Then travel a long distance to help him diagnose and treat him.
We are providing a medical car in Taitung
to his home to provide this service
This may be a very important trend in the future.
Finally, I think what I just said
I know a lot of young people here
I am here
I left Yangming six years ago
Before, of course, the principal had this support at the graduation ceremony.
In 2008
because i left first
so i have facebook
I have Facebook to share with the outside world after graduation
So I'm here to share with you
I remind them that a humble
I see a lot of young people are often like that
Pride South Center
Selfishness is often one's own worst enemy
I see them because they are all excellent
so the world is playing let them go
not us playing let the world go
Also I think a self star is very important
Often the line between cleverness and wisdom
i see too many smart people coming
in Hobbkin
You see teachers and students are very smart
Back to Taiwan too
But when I saw some, he stopped to a certain extent.
Because I don't think they can
He's smart and useless
Instead it becomes a misuse
He starred because of lack of ego
This is actually the self star
so-called wise man
Positive thinking
Often a motivated crew
i am in America
habken is the one
The host of the drama I went to along the South
He did not do a good job in research
But the flying boobs are huge
He sees things as positive
For example, look at
he likes to drink
like a glass of wine
If it is full
Look at what the positive people say
half full
half empty when you say negative
totally depends on how you look at things
then i think he gave me
this is great for me
When I arrive at Yangming
when some colleagues look at me
as if you see things head on
I actually believe I've been greatly influenced by
rather than being caught by a kind of thing
think over there
you can't fix that's a
negative energy
For you
It's not good for your surroundings
dare to try
don't be afraid to fail
Because this is the one I invited Hou Wenyong to give a speech
He just wants to try his dream
If he hadn't made a decision
he is willing to invest
he was just thinking
if i do in the future
how
There is another meaning here
Dare to try
Now at Yang Ming Club we will give the results
there are
Both are 78 points
90 cents what?
I later changed it to ABC
Because we're not as emphatic as they are
These things
that time that
What's the difference of 0.5 points?
what am i lower than you
because that's what you do
Of course you don't imagine seeing
become
during my exam
I dare not write
I'm afraid of being wrong
what happens in this situation
Unknowingly put your model
That creativity will be frosted away
unwilling to try
just think about this
may not be right
I am
my own thoughts
Write down my Feelings
so i tried this
i think it should be
Especially Nation is helpful
During the past few years at the State Department
I think these two are speaking to me
deep understanding
The State Department says a mission-oriented
We have a lot of contact with the government
Then I think it's a bit of reluctance
never give up
Often the thin line between success and failure
Our last year we were fighting for a special budget
that would have been
what we strive for
There are applications for three days on May 1st
I was later told that we were not
I will not give up
so I
I will follow
Director of Correlationism
then explain to them
why i don't help
The result is won
i won't do it
none of us do
just accepted
just no
Here is an example
I think as long as you think it's right
Try your best
something at the end
It's not about the result, it's about the process
In fact, none of them are you Try your best
you have become your best
you have a clear conscience
I want to share this with you guys
Encourage each other
in the end i thought
I think it is very
is to treat people with sincerity
This bag is honest and sincere and you are honest
often mutual trust
The cornerstone of mutual trust
Over the years I have been involved in many
The vaccine during this epidemic
what to negotiate with foreign countries
Including going to OEM and
that pre-purchase
I feel great
The one with AZ
We never knew an Englishman at all
we build trust
Then he took the initiative to let me know many things
Then it can actually help us a lot
So I said I completely believe in this mutual trust
It's very, very important to build
as long as you are sincere
make people feel that you are sincere
can do it
so a conclusion
I'm at Tim today from math to medicine
I want to lay the foundation stone of mathematics
actually very important
But don't and don't encourage
This thing has to be done step by step
This laid foundation is a stone
a tree stacked it
Of course mathematics leads to scientific application
Be sure to take it step by step
I still believe that mathematics is the mother of science
If the application of mathematics can be used in different fields
That often doesn't mean
just jump in
take time
like i spend time
my vision for this
so i'm in hacker
I am most to blame
There are two half days in each week
one is the spirit of discussion
It's their genetic research on April 4th
we all discuss
read the paper together
So my clinical and genetic review of April 4th
I actually have a certain degree of knowledge in this area
because we all discuss
and step by step
then go back to college
I think it is the inevitable mission of the university to cultivate talents like
The key to attaching importance to medical education and keeping pace with reality
I'm talking about, for example, we are now
In the past, I think that medical education emphasizes on cultivating
Right in the hospital is the disease called Q
Actually now it's like an old man fell and broke his hip
The hospital mobilized for surgery, that was a start
Is there a community that can assist him before returning home?
be able to rehab be able to get back to yourself
It's actually a whole set
And university teaching, I think medical teaching also needs to be revised.
In response to future trends, there is an urgent need to be located in the pet mother
we need to be able to understand
It is what we observe that we need to look forward
What is the one that will appear?
advance deployment etc.
It's what we want to see, should we wait until the end
that was too late
The last thing I want to talk about is the routine teaching teacher township head
Never forget the original intention
I just mentioned that I see a lot of college teachers
The research teacher thinks that I have to do research
And forget that the main purpose of the university is to cultivate talents
don't use that as an excuse
And Dang is not willing to spend time with students
including one for teaching and one for education
the two are different
Education includes some courses that I set up
some specifications
Teaching is that this course can arouse students' interest
Then I think everyone must not forget
This is the original intention of our university
thank you all
Thanks
Academician Liang Principal Liang Principal Liang
Very informative and very moving speech
So now is the time for you to ask questions
we have prepared some gifts
Thank you, Dean Liang, for his wonderful speech
Let me start off by saying that I really want that
Academician Liang has the opportunity to be our Minister of Education
Minister of Health and Welfare, even better, he is the blessing of Taiwan
So my question, a lot of questions, but I'll start with one or two
that is
From a logical point of view, it is
Medicine, as far as we know about Taiwan
doctors can make a lot of money
That's great. It can cure your illness.
From the point of view of prevention
Everyone is healthy and they have no money to make
So what? I guess it's an institutional issue.
how about the system
design can go to boot
Guidance is that doctors are willing
Let's start with the management of the hospital
wish you good health
instead of wishing you sick
But if it's very powerful, help you heal
right
This is the first question
I'll be the first
good
I just proposed to Vice President Liu
just after finishing talking
i am more than happy to stay
tell everyone if
some problems
because time is still limited
so or say
ask each one
or up to two topics
If needed
if there is more
we can talk again
i just asked so consistent
very real problem
preventive mechanism
i may be to the doctor
Then I don't have a job
what to do
i think
this is impossible
there is no single answer
I think I can think of these two
One is in the health insurance payment
Actually we didn't do it
That is to say, it can encourage hygiene
If you do good hygiene
Tell him smoking is bad for David
Then you can also pay
This is a
i understand did
But it's very unreliable
no effect
Here is an example
I think it can be done this way
let there be an incentive to make them work
In addition, I think it is humanistic
Do you want to forget you no matter what
Are you part of society?
whether you are a doctor
You are a construction worker in the workplace
They're all part of society, right?
Yes or no
That should be seen from the whole big letter
don't just look at yourself
If you have such a mind
will do it
then we'll be forever
It is the institution that built the insurance
keep eating it
I'm wondering now
these points
But I have come into contact with many
Actually there are
i'm happy to be there
Yang Ming more than seven years
interact with many students
I'm glad to see
Many people go to the field of public health
build that health system up
i think i think there is hope
good
if there is still a problem
after we finish the speech
It's the lady behind the raised hand
Good evening
To my understanding
Education today
seems to focus on the pedagogical side
and
it seems to me that
they go more for
what comes afterwards on mercenary
grounds than the knowledge level
So how do you try to improve on that
especially in countries like
in Asia
I mean the part of you say
it seems to emphasize more on
pedagogical the teaching side
Okay
You want me to
straight
deinen can't speak Mandarin
you
ok you use yours
Kenyuan
Then I think I can use Chinese
so that we can compare
I don't think it's just medicine now
It is no longer possible to rely solely on traditional teaching methods
So in fact for Kenya all kinds of different
Like PBL, I just mentioned that Problem-based learning is a way
just totally unconventional
it's in a room
just a table
Then there is a blackboard for everyone to discuss
That is to say, this interactive
This way is actually very important
Instead of tradition is teaching one
is one to many
this is very important
So I think everyone needs to change this concept.
it is possible to do
again at the same time
I also want to say by the way
That is to say, what we often hear is Mux
have you heard this
what is that called
just record it first
Is it called Mux
what is Chinese
Do you know what I'm talking about?
The teacher may record it first
a lesson
a course
Then you can provide
i think
This is an example
we use high tech
But don't be high tech
driven by high tech
You have to use take advantage
high tech can offer to you
but not the other way around
because i feel like that mox
for its what's advantage of having a mox
for those who
for those who may not
he might not be that better
well prepared
see before
watch this video
or see it later
unforcement
is helpful
but not replacement
especially in medical education
I am I to I context
interactive
this conversation
then i will
the whole introduction
conversation to me
Well, Dean Liang, thank you
you first
Dean Liang, thank you, the police have spoken
I want to ask you is
You mentioned several times in your speech
It's about research
i want to ask
As a researcher
the most important thing is
Except that he loves his own research
This topic also has maintain
other than his interest
usually required to have
other traits or something
During your teaching career
I am
I can say that the most important thing is
find interest
we were
I was before going abroad
How many years ago did that go abroad
Before 1974 and 1954
At that time it was computer science
most popular time
many people go out
No matter what I read, I read computer
work early
but i think again
After he finds someone to work
his every day
can he
Are they happy?
is he doing what he wants to do
So I think interest is very important
I just mentioned our field
I can go to work in a pharmaceutical factory
I choose to do this
because I am interested in research
But don't think I'm like this
I said don't go to the drug factory
Actually, I was thinking later
people who work in a pharmaceutical factory
He actually contributed more directly to mankind than us
Because working with Condition
develop a new drug
so
everyone does different things
but no matter what
find out what your interests are
I think it's the most important
that interest can be cultivated
that can go first
So be sure to open mind
to understand
no presupposition
then talk to different
can arouse your interest
that interest is important
then the second
i would actually like
I think this some mentality
that is to say
that's easy to say
means don't be afraid to fail
as i just said
we must
We all go through setbacks
I asked Vice President Liu
well done
I think it must be in the middle
I also encountered this time
this paperberryjack these
But as long as you feel that what you want to do
to pursue
At the same time, we must open mind
to discuss with different people
I just said that the head of my department
He obviously didn't do it
But he is a very good mentor
Like when I wrote the first grant
write it out to others
I send that to NH
Actually what is that title?
He listens to me
He gave me a good title
Then we write paper
If some comments
i don't know how to respond
he gave me good answers
So mentoring is actually very important
i think some young people
This is also what I think in the senior
we are going to roleplay
one unit
if you wish him well
you want him young to get up
So our role is to develop young people
So I was influenced by the head of the department
So I'm more experienced
i play this role
I mentor young people
only two left
I happen twice
The two of them started their business and can take PSC students
Don't think you can be a professor
you are still in the old time
So I see students looking for me
Because I am now a senior and I have this reply
I just said I'm coming with this one
supervised you
I'm going to take her as your manufacturing professor
Throughout the process I wanted to take
In the beginning we brought together
I provide her with reference on how I can interact with students
I will ment her again
Then the first person asked the student what happened afterwards.
he published articles
My colleague asked me why I wanted to help co-author
I still think of what my professor said at the time
I'm not involved
i don't want
the first young professor
Now the head of the department
I think it's the other way around
I encourage each other with senior people
Have the heart to be willing to train young people
Young people must have a heart
feel nothing
Didn't say it was an ugly question
It seems that I feel very shameless
no such thing
Would you like to go to Open Mind
to ask different questions
The other is to participate in Seminars in different fields
Don't just cling to your lab
or your institute
hear some other fields
good to know
Only your vision will collapse
Maybe one day because of listening to him
This handles bypassing
Therefore, the two sides can cooperate better
time relationship we are now
last question
Maybe the microphone must be on
Is there anything
What statistical software are you familiar with?
Or learn about business databases
An environment that allows you to avoid chest risks
Then genes live younger
what environment to avoid
dangerous environment
chest risk
that is...
very advanced environment
blood in blood
Danger
dangerous environment
i context i have nothing
that is
avoid here
let's talk once
Are you familiar with any statistical software?
or business database
A bloody environment can be avoided
Then genes live younger
live younger
actually
Taiwan now
In recent years the government has promoted
Health big data integration platform
is to put different
big data combined
Not just health insurance information
like that
they also have that
our cloud
take that imaging
can all be put together
Now just more and more
if put together
has been more and more
more and more
I will be more prosperous
but i think it is
I don't know if I have
answer you like this
I said young
I think it's new
I just said that our principal has an appointment
In fact, we are with young people
we actually think
My wife and I both feel that
he only talks about us
We are young at heart
we will not age
But we feel young at heart
I think that is the most important
Finally, the big data you mentioned
I just express
my own opinion
This is completely personal opinion
we all talk now
data science or something
I have some reservations about this
I think too much emphasis on data
Data is part of our science
Our collection is the answer to your questions
you better ask
what question do you want to ask
I think this is the most important
So I should make a result
I don't know how to explain it in the future
what was the original question
I don't have a main answer like this
I just want to say that you mentioned big data
We have a lot of data
now facing this
As you can see, it's just a matter of sight
This is actually
many things are not
two sides of one body
I think both parties need to understand
Why is it important
But from another point of view
Because making good use of big data can improve human
health helps
I think this goes for both
have to take care of
Our data definitely has
Big data definitely has
I'm here to remind everyone
When you use it, ask first
what question do you want to answer
I think this is the most important
i think there are still many questions
But we also have to
come to an end
advance notice
September 27
can speak
This time from Fang to Changshou
unlock
common momentum
very, very good speech
We also listen to this influence
ok then thank you
Thank you very much Dean
Academician Liang Xiaochang
very good speech
Thanks
thank you all